Hey. Hey. Hey.
Heat. Heat.
Good evening and good day everybody and
welcome back to the Ask a Bijit Show.
This is episode 344.
We are discussing what's happening in
the world. We are going to discuss Iran,
the war on Iran. We're going to discuss
that. Uh and always as always before we
begin, let me see who all is there on
the live chat. I can I will greet some
of you. Uh Daran Patel Mojour uh
geopolitical dub from Indor good to see
you sir Alkashikari good evening Anush
Ankush Sharma photography here we are
really now Miss Patel namaste abishekla
live uh 24 bharat abishekla live once
again dhiraj kamat mna kotari says it's
a very pleasant evening in Bangalore
it's raining I'm glad uh mahul rajesh
babu
wanendra up hares madu real painter
Good to see you. Sam Brahmanic namaste.
An du namaste. Sar Ashwani Sharma. Uh
hello Nirj Bhardwaj. Arvind KR Singh.
Nirvana Shanks. Uh a Nirvana Shanks son.
Uh Arvind KR Singh once again. Um who
else do we have? Uh
okay. SKR
7733 Akam Jot Abishek Shukla live once
again from Kpur I haven't been to Kpur
love would love to come there prardana
namaste Nirvana Shanks once again so
0709 from Jaipur I think yes uh
geopolitical dubal Vladimir Putin who
else do we have uh good to see real
Vladimir Putin as always and polomial 4
kahan from sake Delhi swastik
good Morning Ashwin R9889.
This is Harsh Kapoor. Full support. Full
support to you as well. Swastik Koh uh
Kahan Tech G Chat DSP. Namaste. Good to
see you. Chat DSP. It's been a while.
Good to see you. Um
Vehav
Kumar Deangan. All right. Meet Mistri
Kamcho. Yes. All good. Shishri Sriuri.
Good evening ma'am. Shishir. Greetings.
Kahan Sastik Koh Yashwant Sudir Raguir
Soleni Shre Smitra is here from Moscow.
Good uh good evening gravity ab111.
Okay, Pranam U sorry this is Hush Kapoor
Nutan Roshan good to see you O are
precious talks good evening uh Vibhav
Vincadesh Dirj Kamat U Sagar G Namaskar
Ready always ready good to see you
Ankush Sharma once again u and lots of
lots of other people Saturu Guru good to
see you Saturu Gojo Jay Guman is from
Montreal good morning to you sir Jay
Gumman and so many other people Satu
Gojo Arya
Uh Anime Paratia, good evening. Namaste.
Uh Aneruda Rajniker
Anu
and everybody else. Cintillating kids.
Uh Ajinka Pawar
JRXna. Hello.
And Jagdish Mali Shiv Kapoor from from
LinkedIn was joined from LinkedIn. U Kit
S is here from Dublin, Ireland. Ankit.
Ankit. All right.
Okay, good to see you all. Good to see
you all. So good to have you all on this
live stream. Uh before I take some
questions, let us see what's been
happening in the world. The Americans
looks like they are planning for a
ground invasion. A ground invasion of of
Iran. It looks like that's what they are
planning. Maybe it's a bluff. Maybe it's
a real thing. But let's see what have
been the developments in the past 24 or
so hours. Let's see. So here we have
this. It's by this is a message by the
lieutenant general of the US Marine
Corps. The the commander of the Marine
Forces Reserve and Marine Forces South.
Uh it's from 26th of March. He says
Marines, our nation is in a
consequential moment. Global events are
shaping our nation security and we must
be ready. I asked you direct I ask you
directly are you truly ready to deploy,
fight and win? Are your skills sharp,
your standards high, and your gear
packed prepared for immediate in uh
movement? Is your desert marat readily
available? Is your gear packed and ready
to pick up and move or is it stored away
in a corner of your home? Are your
family's affairs in order when the call
comes? Readiness will be assumed, not
questioned. Your readiness is not a
declaration. It's a daily commitment.
This is not a theoretical exercise. Our
forces are currently engaged in in
operations connected to Iran to Iran
and our position to preserve stability
in the Western Hemisphere. Our enemies
get a vote and a mass mobilization could
become reality. A mass mobilization
could become reality. We are operating
in this environment now. History demands
our readiness today, tomorrow and every
day. Your preparation for for combat is
forged in your daily actions, your
training and the seriousness with which
you uh tackle to you handle every
responsibility. We are we are measured
not by by our intentions but by what we
can do right now. Check your readiness,
tighten your standards, prepare your
family. Our nation expects a disciplined
capable force ready for immediate
action. That force is the marine forces
reserve. That standards begin that
standard begins with and must be held by
you. The fight is on. So, American
Marines are being told to prepare for
combat. Prepare for your family. So,
looks like a ground invasion could be on
the cards. Okay. Uh here we have more
breaking news. The US is preparing for a
potential ground invasion into Iran that
would last for up to two months. As per
the Washington Post, thousands of
American soldiers are arriving in the
Middle East for what could become a
dangerous new phase of the war. Any
invasion would involve raids by a
mixture of special operations forces and
conventional infantry troops. As per
American officials, uh the American
president, Mr. Trump, has wavered
between declaring that the war is
winding down and threatening to amplify
it. As we know, as we know, every other
day he says that the war is almost over.
We've almost won it. Uh discussions over
the past month have touched uh upon the
possible seizure of Kar Island and raids
into other coastal areas near the
straight of Hormuz. The Iran war enters
appears to be entering a new era. So we
could be in for massive uh you know
escalation of the war. What else do we
have? This is the US Central Command
Twitter account. Okay. And they've
posted these photographs of their assets
uh being deployed into the region. US
sailors and marines aboard USS Tripoli
LH A7 arrived in the US Central Command
area of responsibility March 27. The
America class amphibious assault ship
serves as the flagship for the Tripoli
amphibious ready group 31st Marine
Expeditionary Unit composed of about
3,500 soldiers, sailors and marines in
addition to transport and strike fighter
aircraft as well as a amphibious assault
and tactical assets. So I'm not sure
what the central command area of
responsibility is. I suppose we could
Google that. Okay. What's sentcom?
What's the area of responsibility?
So this is that area of responsibility.
Okay. So this uh the US strip has
arrived in the US US sendcom area of
responsibility. So it could be anywhere
between the Red Sea to the U so-called
Arabian Sea to u the Gulf of Oman or
maybe even the uh Persian Gulf. Entering
the Persian Gulf is almost impossible
for them because the Iranians will take
them out. But they could be somewhere in
this region, the scentcom region. This
is the scentcom region. You have US EU
com, US Sentcom, US Afric
or something.
So that's where they have entered. So
the looks like the war could be
escalating soon. And this is an update
from US sentcom the Twitter account
March 28th update. Today is March 29. US
Central Command commenced operation epic
fury against Iran at the direction of
the U president. uh on February 28 as we
know um sentcom forces are t striking
targets to dismantle the Iranian
regime's security apparatus prioritizing
locations that pose an imminent threat.
They see they claim to have struck more
than 11,000 targets. They claim to have
undertaken 11,000 more than 11,000
combat flights and they claim to have
damaged or destroyed more than 150
Iranian vessels so far. And they have
all these assets that they have deployed
in air and sea and land. Patriot
interceptor missile systems, THAAD
anti-bballistic missile systems. Those
have been destroyed mostly or they've
run out of uh interceptors. But yes,
they have put this entire list out of
all kinds of aircraft and naval assets
and land assets. What else? Type of
targets. What are the different types of
targets they've taken out? Yeah. Yeah.
So they've listed the the types of
targets and that's yeah that's an update
from these folks here. Um you know as we
know
oil is becoming a major issue as a
consequence of this really stupid war.
Okay looks like various parts of the
world are going to start running out
okay of oil or at least the deliveries
from the Persian Gulf region the
straight of Hormuz region will stop
soon. So uh for the US region it will
stop by April 15th. For the EU region,
it will stop by April 10th. For Africa,
by March 22, April 1st, which we are
already into. For Australia, by April
20. And for East Asia, April 1st. India
is the closest to the straight of Hormuz
actually, right of of among the major
civilized nations or major nations. So,
India is the closest to the straight of
Hormuz. And uh we will have to see what
happens visav India. So India consumes
about 2.3
uh million barrels per day okay of uh of
oil. China consumes 5.2 million barrels
per per day per day. Taiwan 0.65, South
Korea 2.2, Japan 2.3 and so on. So uh
this is the situation and depending on
how Trump goes ahead with his
escalations and a potential ground
invasion, things could get worse
potentially. So we will have to keep an
eye on this. Um and at the same time
there is escalation happening in the
Ukraine theater right uh so this
accounts as oil seems to be on on its
way to potentially exceeding exceeding
150 uh dollars per barrel. Ukraine has
again bombed Russia's second largest
refinery causing causing a massive escal
explosion.
So yes, Ukraine is working in
conjunction with the Americans and uh as
we can see what's happening in Persia,
it's tied into what's happening in
Ukraine and in Russia and the Ukrainians
are hitting very hard at Russia's oil
production and transportation export
capabilities and Russia seems to be
sitting and taking it right. So this is
going to be a major major problem for
India because see our option our
alternative to what comes from Hormos is
what comes from Russia in terms of oil.
But if Russia's ability to deliver oil
to India is impacted that's going to be
a very significant problem for India as
well as China. Right? So this is what's
happening. Uh the Iranians are taking
out American aircraft. This is an AVAC
aircraft. E3 Century Avac completely
destroyed. The Americans say that it's
been damaged. This is not damage, this
is destruction, right? Um, and this is a
very expensive aircraft and there's only
about 20 something of this aircraft in
in existence and the production line uh
stopped a long time ago. So there these
are precious assets that the Americans
have and the Iranians have hit very
precisely at at this specific point in
the aircraft. So this is what it looks
like. As you can see, it's got this
major this massive radar, you know,
that's that's above the aircraft and
that's what the Iranians have very
precisely very precisely destroyed.
Uh so the Iranians uh they have targeted
the key rear housing surveillance radar
which is the key component. It's an very
expensive and very rare component and
the Iranians have completely destroyed
that.
So here's some analysis by Captain
Titan. Targeting the rear housing
surveillance radar rather than the
aircraft's more obvious components
reveals Iran's targeting Iranian
targeting intelligence office
sophistication that goes beyond knowing
where the aircraft is parked. Right. The
knew which specific subsystem to destroy
to maximize permanent mission kill
probability while minimizing the
munitions required to achieve this. So
the Iranians have been studying American
military doctrine for over four decades.
They've been studying aircraft
architecture and operational
vulnerabilities produced by So this all
of this it produced a targeting decision
precise enough to obliterate an
irreplaceable
$500 million asset through its most
critical and least armored component.
Right? So that's what the Iranians have
achieved. U now Iran says that the US
has until March 30 which is tomorrow
12:00 p.m. Thran time to condemn the
bombing of Iranian universities. And if
the US doesn't do this, Iran will carry
out strikes against multiple American
universities in the Middle East. Right?
So escalation, escalation, escalation.
What else? Okay, this is interesting.
So CNN satellite analysis and Alma
research findings show that Iran's
underground tunnel cities with internal
rail systems that move missiles to blast
door exits, they have survived the
bombing campaign largely intact. Largely
intact. And the geology is the real
defense.
So it's been a month now. The Americans
have been bombarding. They've been
striking at these uh Iranian tunnels.
Okay. Internal underground cities.
Uh but uh it's Iran still keeps firing.
It's not stopped Iran from firing. Of of
course the the number of uh of missiles
launched per day have come down by by
90%. Right. But the precision targeting
it's intact and the number of hits are
actually increasing potentially per day
because the Americans and Israelis have
run out of interceptors mostly. So the
that's why the renants have you know
brought the number of launches down by
90%.
Um but Iran keeps fighting and the
reason is that u the reason does not lie
above the ground but hundreds of meters
behind beneath the ground inside a
network of integr underground missile
cities connected by internal railways
that have been carved into mountains
that no bomb in the current American or
Israeli arsenal can actually reach.
Right. Um,
so,
so what happens is after the Americans
and Israelis bomb the tunnel entrances,
construction equipment appears there
within 48 hours and it digs out the
blocked entrances and restores access to
the tunnels below.
So, the strikes on surface
infrastructure had only temporarily
rendered large missile launch bases
inoperable. any Iranian asset located
within an underground infra within
underground infrastructure the center
concluded survived.
So whatever is below the ground deep
inside all of it survives. The entrances
are destroyed and within 48 hours they
are operationalized all over again. Uh
the central constraint is geological and
it's been publicly stated by Iran
itself. So Iran has built its missile
bases across provinces and cities at
depth at a depth of 500 m. You simply
can't destroy something that's 500 m
underground. The American the most
powerful American uh you know bunker
bust bomb. It can penetrate about 60 m
of reinforced concrete or 40 m of
moderate rock. And these in uh Iranian
assets are built under granite granite
which is harder than moderate rock. So
it's almost impossible. It's it's not
almost impossible. It is impossible for
the Americans to destroy these Iranian
underground uh cities. So yeah, this is
something we discussed yesterday. That's
why I thought I'll uh I'll show you this
thing. Uh then this is a a comment. This
is a tweet by an Indian former diplomat
uh Madame Nirupama Menendra. Who is this
lady? She is a retired civil servant u
who served as India's foreign secretary
from 2009 to 2011 and she was also
India's ambassador to the US to China
and Sri Lanka during her career. Okay.
Very senior retired diplomat. Um now
what has she said? This is this is her
uh geopolitical take. She says that the
world is being reordered by those who
act and by those who define. If India
she says if India wishes to be counted
among those who define it must ensure
that its silence does not speak louder
than its convictions. We are living she
says through a moment when the rules of
the international system are being
rewritten in real time. Assassinations
of leaders, the killing of civilians,
open assertions of force. These are no
longer aberrations but instruments. In
such a world, silence is not neutrality.
It is read, interpreted and often
misread as consent. India has long
claimed a distinctive voice in
distinctive space in global affairs, not
as an appendage to power, but as a voice
shaped by its own civilizational
experience and its history of speaking
for sovereignty, restraint and balance.
India has had a history of moralizing
and lecturing the world. That's what she
is essentially telling you. Okay. And
that voice mattered, she claims because
it was consistent even when
inconvenient. Strategic autonomy cannot
mean adjusting our language to the
hierarchy of power. Restraint has its
place. Calibration is necessary. But
when fundamental questions arise arise,
EM dash about sovereignty, about the
limits of force, about the protection of
civilians. EM dash India cannot afford
to be silent. A moral compass, a moral
compass is not an instrument of foreign
policy. A moral compass is its
direction. Without it, realism drifts
into accommodation and autonomy into
ambiguity. This war has damaged India's
interests in every practical sense. Yes,
that's true. I agree with that. It has
raised costs, narrowed diplomatic room,
stress shipping, etc., etc., etc., etc.,
and injected fresh instability into a
region vital to India's economic and
external strategy. It's done. Yes,
correct. She's right about that. Even if
New Delhi can cushion the blow, it
cannot plausibly claim that the blow
itself serves India. Nobody is claiming
that. Who is claiming that? The deeper
question is whether India is willing to
say so without with sufficient clarity.
So she's putting out facts here. But
over here she's claiming that India
needs to moralize and lecture the world.
And what does that achieve is my
question.
She's saying that we live we are living
through a moment where the rules of the
international system are being rewritten
in real time. That's not the case. We
have always lived in such a time
whenever the US has wanted to wage war,
they have waged war. What was what was
1991?
What was 1991? The uh Iraq war, the
invasion of Iraq. What was that?
The same thing was going on at the time.
2003, the second Iraq war. The second
invasion of Iraq. Same thing, right? A
killing of civilians. Million, maybe a
million Iraqis were killed in this 2003
invasion, right? Open assertions of
force. Exactly. That's what I'm talking
about. Open assertions of force. Uh
assassinations of leader leaders. Well,
the Americans have done that too. Okay.
So, um it's not like it's something new
as she is claiming. But she is claiming
that India should not keep quiet. India
should lecture the world. India should
moralize. We need to have a moral
compass because the war has damaged
India's interests. So by lecturing the
world and saying that you are evil and
you are naughty and you are bad, how
does that serve India's interest and how
does it stop the war from damaging our
interests?
Uh I'm not really sure what she's
claiming but this has been historically
India's diplomacy. It's historically
Indian diplomacy was all about taking
the moral high ground and lecturing the
world and telling the world how it
should behave and it never ever served
India's interests.
My take is very clear. My position is
very clear. India should keep quiet
about these matters. This is not our
war. We did not start it. India to
should take action
that uh limits the damage that this war
is causing to India's interests in
India's economy and so on. India should
take vigorous action as much action as
possible to limit the damage this war
will is causing and will cause
potentially to our interests. That what
that is what we should do. We should not
go and lecture the world and take the
moral high ground that you cannot do
these things. uh you can't assassinate
world leaders, you can't kill civilians,
you can't show open force, naked force,
blatant force, you can't violate the
international uh law, the UN charter,
all those things. What how does that
serve us? How does that serve our our
interests by by lecturing not the world
but the US? Essentially, she she is
implying this lady that India should
lecture the US that you are doing very
naughty stuff. You are being very evil.
That's what she's saying. That's not for
her to do. That's not for the government
of India to do. The government of India
has to act according to certain
parameters. Certain guard rails have to
be in place. Right? India has to be very
diplomatic about this.
See, we cannot afford to offend Donald
Trump.
We don't have to go and suck up to him
or like he like like Donald Trump says,
kiss his ass. India hasn't doesn't need
to do that. But India should do
everything possible not to offend the
guy and the best way to do it is to keep
quiet. Stay out of this matter. We
didn't start this. It doesn't involve
us. It hurts us. So we'll do everything
we we can. We will take actions to
minimize
the the damage to our interests. But we
will keep quiet about this. That is what
India should do. India should not follow
the advice of Madame Nirupama Men and
Rao. This is what India has historically
done under previous governments and it's
never ever served India's interests.
It's always been harmful to India's
interests. Nobody likes somebody who
lectures you.
Yeah. So the world is being reshaped by
those who can act.
So India should take actions. India
should act vigorously to preserve and
safeguard its interests and to mitigate
whatever to to whatever extent the
damage that the war is causing to to our
interests. But there's no point
lecturing Donald Trump and lecturing the
world. That is super annoying and for
someone like Trump it's even more
annoying. So we should not do that. So I
completely disagree with Madame Nirupama
Menan Raalo and her uh take about what
India should be doing. Yeah.
Um, see her her style of diplomacy, it's
outdated.
Okay. It's it's it's now it belongs to
the time of the to the era of the
dinosaurs. Hopefully, as far as India is
concerned, hopefully India's diplomacy
today is very different. It's nation
first, national interest first and we
will do whatever it takes to to to
serve that to serve the national
interest and we don't lecture anybody
anymore. Right? when we are asked about
our interest and why we behave in
certain and we act in certain ways we
can explain that and that's what our
foreign minister has been doing Dr. Dr.
Jashankar for the past I don't know six
seven years yeah he's been doing about
five six years six six plus years he's
been doing that and he's been doing a
good job of a very good job of
communicating our interests and u our
actions the reasons for our actions to
the world and he's done a good job of
that so and and it will be very clear
that Dr. Jashundra has or Prime Minister
Modi has never lectured anybody as to
how they should behave, what's right and
what's wrong and what is the moral
morally correct thing to do. None of the
nonsense we've we've done the past uh I
don't know 10 11 years and that is the
right approach and that is what madame
minra disagrees with and I completely
disagree with her. All right. All right.
Now let's take some questions. Let's
take some questions. What's going on in
the world? Let's answer your questions.
Divu says 1947 balkcanization of BAT was
primarily a geopolitical move not a
religious one. Agree or not? Can you
please do an analysis by of why it was
strategic for the British to make the
border specifically where they did?
Look um
Bat was balconized in 1947. We know that
right now was this a geopolitical move
or a religious one? So if you read
Indian authors, Indian historians etc.
they will say India was divided on the
basis of religion. It is religion that
caused the balkcanization of India.
That's what you all believe. But the
truth is religion was weaponized
to bal to achieve the balkcanization of
India.
Okay. So various see for example the
kilafhat movement
the kilafhat movement
um
I suppose a lot of people at least in
previous generations before today were
under the impression that kilafhat meant
kilaf means you're opposing the British
and it was Mr. Gandhi who mainstreamed
the kilafhat movement right the kilafhat
movement was started what was it all
about say in 1918 1990 1920 around that
time Mustafa Kabalat the great Turkish
dictator the great man he was in the
process of abolishing the institution of
the caliphate the kilafhat
okay he he his objective was to make
Turkey completely secular completely
democratic and no Sharia law, no kilaf,
no khif, no nothing. And the last sultan
of Turkey, Abdul Hammed,
he was expelled from Turkey. He was
exiled from Turkey by Mustafa.
So this process was ongoing between 1918
to 1920 something early 1920s and the
world began to sense that the the
institution of the caliphate would be
ended by Mustafa Kabal and that's why
various Muslims around the world wanted
to protest that. So there was this
movement that began in India as well a
fringe movement that nobody knew about
excuse me and it was Mr. Gandhi who
mainstreamed this movement and urged
every Indian to participate in the
kilafhat movement and most Indians I
suppose imagine that this was a movement
to protest the British occupation of
India but it was a movement
to preserve the caliphate and to
preserve Sharia law
and even later in the 1960s '7s ' 80s '
90s the way this was taught in India's
history books it was like it was this
moment was opposing the British.
It was never explicitly spelt out that
this was a movement in support of Sharia
law and the institution of the
caliphate.
So Mr. Gandhi and and this this the
kilafhat movement failed. Obviously
Mustafa did indeed abolish the
caliphate. It still stands abolished
today. Right? But this movement the
kilafhat movement which Mr. Gandhi
championed
what it did is that it became the
precursor
the chemical precursor to the Pakistan
movement. Okay. And the British knew
that eventually some at some point in
time they will have to vacate India.
They will have to leave India. But they
wanted to leave India in a certain shape
and form that would be beneficial and
advantageous to their continuing
geopolitical interests in this region
which is the subcontinent and beyond
which includes West Asia okay and also
central Asia and the Indian Ocean
region. So the British had decided they
would partition and balconize India so
that India doesn't remain unified so
that they have access so that the the
the Indian nation doesn't become great.
It is denied access to central Asia and
there will always be a mercenary
garrison state an artificial temporary
nation called Pakistan or whatever it
would be called
that will continue to serve British
interests because the British will have
caused its its creation. So those who
who rule Pakistan will always always be
subservient to the British. It was
structured in that manner.
Right? Um so what were these interests
of the British? What were the interests?
The interests first of all was first one
interest was to ensure that India
doesn't become remain unified and become
powerful and become quickly in 2030
years a challenger to the west. Right?
That is that was always a possibility.
If someone like Subbash Bose had been
the leader of India of and and he would
not have allowed a partition then in
2030 years India would have become a
different kind of beast.
Right? Because he would not have applied
the Nuvian rate of growth of 3% per
year. He would have done reforms that
would have shot up India's economy and
the Indian economic growth rate would
have been maybe 8 10 12% per year. When
you are a destroyed economy, it's very
very easy to rapidly build it up, right?
So they didn't want that. They did not
want India to rise up again and become a
challenger to the west to British
interests because at the time Brit
Britain was the major superpower, right?
Well, until the 1920s at least, but they
still imagined that they were a major
global power, the British. Secondly,
they wanted
um something to counterbalance a broken
India. Counterbalance India and always
keep India off balance. That would be
Pakistan, right? And Pakistan would also
serve the purpose of denying India
access, its historical access to Central
Asia. In the past, our ancestors
whenever they had to go to Central Asia,
they would just walk into walk into
Central Asia. It would take the process
would take a month or two, but you could
reach Central Asia just by walking or by
going on horseback or whatever. So,
India historically had for thousands of
years access to Central Asia. That was
cut off for India. And then Pakistan
could always u you know supply soldiers
and supply military um you know give
military support to any British actions
in in in West Asia in the Gulf region.
At the time we do not have the UAE and
all these nations you had the crucial
states. So the Gulf region was being
reshaped at the time by the British and
by the by the by the west right u so all
these things.
So there were multiple interests that
the the British had and these were
geopolitical interests. The British
wanted access to central Asia through
the subcontinent region and Pakistan
would provide that. Right? So by by so
magnanimously allowing
uh the the proponents of Pakistan to
create an artificial nation and by
supporting that artificial nation
through economic and other means they
ensure that it will it will always
remain loyal to the west for a price.
But that is fine. Everything comes at a
price.
So they weaponized religion. Okay. And
the roots of this go back to the 19th
century of weaponizing religion,
non-Indian religions, right? Those were
that those that one religion was
weaponized. The roots go back to the
19th century. Uh
and that's how this was done. So this
was primarily I agree with you this was
a geopolitical move not a religious one
but it was done under the pretext of
religion. the religion was weaponized
and that's how this was made to happen.
Okay. U the borders exactly specifically
it's not like the borders exactly had to
be the way they are specifically right
now. The borders could have been
whatever could have been something else
potentially they wanted to give as much
land as possible to Pakistan
even land that was not supposed to be
part of Pakistan. That's how the British
that's why the British started the
Kashmir issue. The first time the flag
of Pakistan was raised in Jammu and
Kashmir, it was done by British officers
under the command of British officers.
So the British ensured that the
Pakistanis, you know, grabbed some
portion some pieces of Kashmir and Mr.
Nehu ensured that that remained with
Pakistan even though Mr. Patel wanted
the Indian army to you know take P back
PJK back.
So yeah, long story but it was primarily
a geopolitical move not but yeah we
Indians see everything from a religious
perspective. So Indians think of this as
a religious matter.
Aditya Achara says a little off topic
but if karma can't be scientifically
proven
then why isn't it if karma can't be
scientifically proven then why isn't it
marketed as something that one has to
pay back in the same lifetime only the
world would be a much better place out
of fear at least
so you saying that maybe it should be
marketed as something that one has to
pay back in the same lifetime only uh
book let me so I'm not sure exactly what
you're asking but let me explain the way
I see karma okay the concept of karma is
has a very strong connection to the
concept of rebirth reincarnation so what
is karma to put it very simplistically
the way a physicist would see things
karma is a law of conservation it's a
conservation law in physics we have laws
of conservation of physical quantities
law of phys law of conservation of
energy, law of conservation of mass, law
of conservation of um of of momentum and
so on so forth, right? We have
conservation laws in physics.
Now,
the law of karma is a conservation law,
but it relates to something that is
non-physical.
The law of karma is the law of
conservation of the merits and demerits
of your actions over multiple lifetimes.
That is the law of karma. Okay. So, it's
not a physical law. It's you could say
it's a spiritual or religious or
whatever it is. Yeah. It it it goes
beyond physics for sure. It's
non-physical.
So, that's what karma is. The it's a law
of conservation. Law of conservation of
the merits and demerits of your actions
over multiple lifetimes. Now, in the
west, we have these they have these
sayings like karma is a and karma
bites back and all that stuff, right? So
when somebody is is known to be a bad
person and something bad happens to
them, they say you know that's that's
karma in action. But that is not
correct.
Karma is something that that you know
operates over multiple lifetimes. So
that's why you know according to Indian
philosophy in India's Indian um culture
lots of people get away with with very
bad things in their lifetimes. You know
you will see many there are people who
are really evil really bad and nothing
bad happens to them. So the law of karma
is that you know what you wait let the
guy die let that person be reborn. We
will never know where the person is
going to be reborn but they going to
experience the merits and demerits both
of their actions over over multiple
lifetimes. So that's what karma is. So
you
so that's how it operates. It's not
supposed to operate in the same
lifetime. It's supposed to operate or
multiple lifetimes. So, you may get away
with very nasty stuff in one lifetime,
but when you're reborn, you're going to
pay for those actions. That is how it
works. And that's how I see it. Um,
and uh I don't know how it can be
marketed or not. It I would say you
can't uh distort what it is, right?
Um, none of these things can be proven
scientifically.
But you cannot distort the meanings of
what these what these of of these
concepts. You can't
otherwise you are doing exactly what the
west keeps doing. They appropriate our
culture and distort it and distort it
out of shape. So I would highly
recommend we don't do that. Okay.
PP Singh says, "I heard on a podcast a
retired Indian Navy commander after the
sinking of the ship of Sri Lanka say in
tropical waters around India submarines
are near undetectable. Then why does the
Indian Navy keep building them?" So a
retired Navy commander said that
submarines are nearly undetectable.
Right?
Isn't that a great thing that if you
have a submarine, nobody can detect it
or it's nearly undetectable?
Then doesn't it make sense for the
Indian Navy to keep building more and
more and more? These are very dangerous
assets that operate unseen below the
waters of the ocean and it's almost
impossible to detect them. So why should
we not build 500 of those if we have the
funds?
The more the merrier.
If they are undetectable, isn't it a
good thing? Isn't it a valuable thing
for the navy? So, doesn't it make sense
that India should India will build more
of those? Will will want to acquire more
of those?
Why does it perplex you, sir?
And it's not like they are nearly
undetectable only in tropical waters
around India. They are undetectable in
all kinds of waters. They are
undetectable in Arctic and Antarctic
waters, in the antl in the in the
Atlantic Ocean, in the Pacific Ocean, in
warm waters, in freezing waters. They're
undetectable everywhere.
They can be detected only when they're
close to the surface. And you know, then
you have these magnetic anomaly
detectors in certain aircraft that can
potentially pick up signatures, you
know, magnetic signatures of uh
submarines.
And you can perhaps try to detect them
through sonar and so on but it's very
very hard to detect submarines and
that's why the Indian Navy seeks to have
more of these. All right.
Sergeant Skylin says your thoughts on
drill India drill. I am not aware of
what that is but I would imagine that
it's about drilling for oil. Is it is
that what what it's about? Uh so if it
is that then I would say it's a great
thing. India needs to drill and and look
for oil and and discover uh reserves of
oil. India has been very lax in this
matter. Yeah. So it's important for
India to to to discover its own
sovereign reserves, resources, petroleum
and oil uh reserves or gas as well.
Sachv Satyajjit says will try to occupy
what's
will try to occupy Iran or parts of Iran
especially after a AF is Afghanistan.
What's um I don't know what is. I
suppose it's US. US US will the US try
to occupy Iran, parts of Iran,
especially after Afghanistan? Looks like
they they may be in the process of uh
you know planning an invasion looks like
that. I in my opinion it's going to be
extremely extremely difficult for them
to make this happen to successfully even
hold on to a to some territory.
um attempting an invasion of Iran is
nearly suicidal in my opinion, but let's
see. Looks like they're going to attempt
this.
Rush Bir says central higher authority
is taking emergency meetings as like
COVID. So, as citizen, what steps should
we take or how worse will it be? See
the problem is the short potential
impact on oil deliveries to India and
gas deliveries to India. Right?
So that's what the government is trying
to take steps to mitigate to maybe some
some steps that will mitigate the uh
effects of this right the delterious and
harmful effects of this on on our
nation. So what what steps can we take
or should should we take as citizens?
Well, don't waste energy, right? It's
summer time, so obviously you're going
to need ACS. You can't I can't tell you
all to not use ACs, but uh and when it
comes to cooking gas and cooking all of
that. So don't take trips you don't
need. So that will ensure that you know
you're not wasting
petrol, diesel, whatever, right? Stay in
your home. If you have a car, if you got
a vehicle, use it only when required.
Don't go for joy rides. Cut cut down on
that. If you're cooking,
don't overcook. Don't don't waste gas if
you're using, you know, LPG or whatever
gas. So, there's a small things citizens
can do and hopefully it makes a
difference. Beyond that, what can
citizens do? Nothing much. Nothing
nothing beyond that I suppose, right?
Individually, we can ensure that we
don't waste energy. That's what we can
do. Beyond that there's nothing citizen
can do and the government needs to take
care of the rest.
YT beyond border said says India could
help Iran now for breaking Pakistan
later.
Um
see I know that we in India are very
very focused on Pakistan. We are laser
focused on Pakistan. Uh but Iran is not
going to help India achieve its its
objectives right now. See,
Iran is is fighting for its survival.
Okay. Now, if India helps Iran, do you
understand the consequences of that? Do
you understand the consequences, sir?
What happens is any nation that helps
Iran is going to be automatically seen
as an enemy, as an adversary by the
United States. Now, do you want the US
to categorize India as an enemy?
They will not simply put a tag on India
as an enemy. They will take actions
against India. We want access to
American markets. We want American
goodwill.
Okay? And that's why India should remain
neutral in this matter. Oh Pakistan
break, let's go and help Iran. It
doesn't work like that. And even if we
help Iran for example, how does it break
Pakistan? How
and don't you think that we our our
military resources like missiles,
arms, ammunition,
drones, whatever we have. Don't you
think we need to conserve those
so that in case the Chinese do some
mischief, we can deal with them. Don't
you think that these are things that we
have to conserve? Right? So it doesn't
make sense for India to get involved in
this matter. the war against Iran or the
war or on whatever side India should
remain completely neutral. All right.
Al Kashukari says, "What happens to
gases, ice, water vapors left behind by
a comet in outer space? What happens to
these things?" Um they become more and
more diffused over time. So let's say
you have a comet. Okay, a comet. What is
a comet? A comet consists of multiple
things. There is rock,
there is ice, and there is dust
all over. So it's a comet is like, in
case you know what snow is like, it's
like a dirty snowball. Not a white
snowball, but a brown or black snowball.
Dirty snowball. That's what a comet is
like. Some comets are rocky, but they
have a lot of, you know, ice on in them.
Some comets are mostly ice. So typically
a comet is a rocky core, a core which is
rocky and around it it's it's got ice
and all that.
So a comet typically originates in the
earth cloud which is way way beyond what
we see of the solar system. Okay. But
sometimes because of some you know u
collisions or maybe because of some
object that that tugs it gravitationally
sometimes these dirty snowballs they get
pulled into the into a different orbit
which then takes them near the sun. Okay
it's typically an elliptical orbit
elliptical orbit. Some comets they they
come once in a million years. Some
comets come every 76 years like Hal's
comet and so on. uh some comets are
short period comets every every few
years like 5 10 years they come right
near the sun. So when a comet comes near
the sun the when it starts approaching
the sun and comes close it's close
enough for the sun's heat to start
affecting it that's when the the the ice
starts melting and it starts shooting
out dust into space and that's how when
the comet comes near the sun it starts
developing this tail this glowing tail
the tail is the tail is mostly water
vapor and dust Okay. So that's how and a
comet will then go around the sun. Okay.
And then go back and once it starts
going back, it starts getting colder and
it stops having the tail. So it's it's a
fleeting phenomenon. It lasts a few
days, a few weeks, right? Uh a few
months sometimes. So what happens to the
ice, ice, gas, water vapor? It all
disperses in space and it becomes
eventually part of the vacuum. So it
just disperses, right? it stays there in
space. So eventually the water
molecules, so let's say it's water
molecules, H2O molecules, right? So
eventually they'll start dispersing and
the mean distance between two water any
two water molecules, it keeps
increasing, increasing until it it's
like they're essentially isolated.
That's what happens. They disperse and
diffuse away.
Rush BR says the US playing on more than
one front. Cuba at Cuba, Russian aid
gets attacked. eventually it sports by
Ukraine.
Let me um US playing on more than one
front at Cuba. Russian aid gets attack
eventually its ports by
Ukraine.
She pledged for Taiwan 2027 Iran war
month world war. What is the question?
Russian aid gets attacked eventually
it's okay. So are you saying that there
have been attacks on Russian aid in
Cuba?
Uh
I know that Russia has been attacked in
its ports by Ukraine. We know that
she pledged for Taiwan 2027. Well,
that's a rumor that we have. uh we don't
have confirmation of that but it looks
like potentially she may have president
of China may have given a deadline of
2027 to his armed forces for taking
Taiwan which is next year. Yep. Um yeah
okay there is that cub Cuba is being
blockaded by the United States. Cuba is
being deprived of power.
Okay. So Cuba is a nation that doesn't
produce oil. So they need to import oil
from wherever Venezuela, Russia,
whatever. The Americans are blockading
Cuba and preventing anyone from
delivering oil to Cuba.
Okay? Whether it is processed or refined
or or unprocessed, whatever. And that's
why Cuba is is now facing power
shortages.
There was this hospital in Cuba that
went dark and apparently everybody who
was in the ICU died who was on oxygen,
babies, elderly people, whatever. So
that's what's going on. And maybe the
Americans are planning to invade Cuba
sometime in the future, sometime perhaps
near future. I don't know. We'll see.
Um, Ukraine is attacking Russian ports.
I discussed that in detail multiple
times. Uh, she's pledge on Taiwan.
That's a rumor. We don't know about that
whether it's true or not, but uh, we'll
see. Iran war month war. I don't know
what it means.
The question you may be asking is, is
this going to lead to a world war? I
hope not. But if there's a American
invasion of of of Iran, I think China
and Russia may get more involved than
what we what they are right now and that
could lead to a situation where this
escalates and more nations get dragged
in. If the American if a hypothetical
American invasion of Iran doesn't go
well, okay, then they may force NATO
nations to get involved and that could
then, you know, we could start
considering this to be a world war. So,
I hope it doesn't happen, but it could
happen.
It could happen.
Yeshuan Prakash, thank you very much.
Yes Prakash.
Aiden Trestler says, "We elected a
clown. He made the world a circus." I'm
Yeah, it is.
I can't It's It's hard to disagree with
what you're saying. Yeah, unfortunate
for the entire world.
Okay. Rahul says, "How to learn French
or German for masters abroad?" I don't
know how to learn French or German. I
mean the best way to learn a new
language is by immersing yourself in
that 24 hours by 7. Yeah. You do that
for a couple of weeks where you all you
do is you communicate in that language.
So that is the fastest way to learn a
language.
Um
um yeah but I suppose there are courses
and apps and whatnot. There's Dualingo
that you can download on your phone. I
don't know if it's a paid app or not but
um there are apps that are available
that will teach you other languages or
there are courses available um we have
what we have these platforms called uh
Corsera, Skillshare whatever on which
you will have courses uh for various
languages. So I I don't know how to
learn languages. I I speak non-Indian
languages. I speak French, right? How
did I learn? I was a kid. I don't even
know how I learned. I was immersed in a
French-speaking environment. I suppose I
just picked it up within 3 months. I was
speaking French within 3 months. So I
did not ever go to French classes or
whatever. One day I I discovered I'm
just speaking French. Yeah. So that's
how I learned. So I don't know how to
learn a language formally. You don't
start by learning grammar, grammatical
rules and all that. The best way to
immer is to immerse yourself. Try and
communicate start communicating as
quickly as possible. Learn the first,
you know, the most important 100, 200
words. Learn basicish grammar-ish,
basicish grammar and start communicating
in in broken German, broken French,
whatever.
So the the the see how do you learn how
to ride a bicycle? You don't study the
mechanics and physics of bicycle
bicycles, right? You sit on a bicycle
and somebody pushes you and somebody
steadies you and you do that for a few
hours and eventually you find that
you're balancing yourself, right? So,
and and you fall a few times, you get
hurt a few times, right? That's how you
learn learn to ride a bicycle. The same
thing goes for languages. You don't
learn by by studying the language. You
learn you learn by doing by speaking the
language and eventually start writing.
Yeah. So, okay.
Okay. IPK Vanessa says Major Dij on
Twitter said things about you. I'm sad.
Who cares?
Who cares? Somebody said something about
me. Who cares? Why are you sad? I'm not
sad.
Don't be so um I would I would recommend
to everybody. Don't let words affect
you. Someone said something nasty. Why
does it hurt your feelings? Laugh it
off. The problem, See,
it's it's it's something that's routine
for me. People take digs at me. People
say nastiest things about me on Twitter
or in in YouTube comments. And I suppose
the objective is to lower my morale,
make me feel bad. But those people don't
know that I have very thick skin. It
makes no difference to me whatever what
they think, what they say. I don't care
one bit about what somebody thinks of
me. I simply don't care.
So let somebody major diguja whatever
say whatever they want to say I simply
don't care it makes no difference to me
it doesn't affect me at all so please
don't let it affect you all right unless
it is something unless this this
gentleman is somebody you respect in
that case well what can I say
all right so so don't be sad okay
praash thank you very much indeed sir
thank
Wun Bajaj says, "Please you use Grock
for YouTube live streams research. It's
the most truthful AI far better than
Google's. Yesterday Google AI lied on
the UN slave trade thing, but Grock did
not. I tested Grock. Should I use
Grock?" So, uh, I don't use it for
research, right? I simply Google
something and Google has its AI. So, for
example, let's let's do this, right? Um,
let's let's try this. It's an
interesting thing you're saying. So let
me let's test this out. Uh so let's try
the same thing on Google. So I am simply
doing a Google search but now the first
result is always AI. How did India vote
on the recent UN resolution about the
transatlantic slave trade?
Let's see.
So now okay where is AI mode? Here we
have it.
So sometimes you have to go into AI
mode. sometimes it it throws the AI
stuff AI summary at you without you
asking for it. So I generally prefer not
to use AI. I prefer to just you know
search for things on Google itself,
right? Uh but but yeah, AI is becoming
ubiquitous today. AI is entering all all
spheres and all domains of everything.
Facebook, the Guardian. So I actually
prefer to do a Google search but then
Google throws it AI at me. So what is
Grock like I suppose I want to log into
Grock and all. So actually I I don't
trust AI summaries.
I like to see news from a Google search.
Uh but but thank you for the suggestion.
I will look into how useful Grock is or
not. I suppose you'll have to buy some
kind of subscription, right? The free
version of Grock won't be very useful.
I'm pretty sure how much the cost is not
an issue, but uh I I'll look into it.
I'll I'll I'll play around with Grock
and see see how how useful it is and
okay. So, thank you for the
recommendation. I'll I'll I'll take it
take you up on this. I'll look into
grock how how good or not gro Grock is
polomial says gate 26 exam was
compromised okay statistically
impossible scores and exam center
clustering gate is for entrance to IIT
for masters PhDs jobs in public sector
units ISRO DRDO education and research
not a priority for this government I'm
sad to hear this I am not aware of this
let me see what's happened so let's so
let's see
gate 2026 exam Um
I said exam not exams but okay
duh. So it doesn't say anything about um
what happened. So this is the this is
the Google AI summary right I am looking
for this stuff here but it it gives you
a summary without you asking for it.
Okay
problems
the controversy. Okay. Controversy
um technical glitches suspected cheating
incident shift towards complex
application based questions over direct
formulas.
Uh let's see controversy.
controversy
or like you're saying compromised
what happened significant allegations
and controversy surrounding the
integrity of the GATE 2026 exam
conducted by IIT Guhati allegedly okay
potential compromises allegations of
cheating compromised centers
some top ranks belong to individuals
with no clear documented history of high
level preparation of coaching or
coaching
uh hana module allegation whatever that
is demand for action data science and AI
focus
okay
unfair AIdriven practices
so this is so I I don't know exactly
what the deal is but this is nothing new
for the Indian education system it's a
rotten third grade education system I
promise you that Iran has a better
education system in India way better
than India's education system and some
individuals in India imagine that this
is how India will become a vishwaguru
with having a third rate education
system like this right so what can I say
it's it's just sad the situation
the state of the education system and
there is no plan for improving things
because there's already this new what
new education policy 2020 or whatever
that is that's been that is in the
process of being implemented and the
government claims this is going to solve
all our problems it's not going to solve
any problem and this will be implemented
by I don't know 20 let's ask the Google
AI what it says okay
by when will the new education policy
2020 be implemented in India
what's it say by 2030 2040 so next 20
years they will slowly implement this
thing and it is not the right solution
so it means that no new solution will be
looked for until 2030 2040 that's it we
are cooked we are cooked I will
recommend those of you who can for
education please go abroad India's
education system is rotten rotten
very sad very unfortunate and I promise
you that Iran has a far better education
system than India
you think of Iran as this poor miserable
little broken nation it's got a far
better education system than India it
produces worldclass talent
yeah
Okay, Chetan says civil war in India
after 189 years and why I am not talking
about this end of civilization when no
I don't want any civil war I have never
said there's going to be a civil war in
India
right after 80 90 years and why no end
of Indian civilization look the way
things are going India is becoming more
and more dassinated right the education
system is a very major factor in this in
dassinating Indians today Indians don't
even know what their culture
You destinate
multiple generations over you know one
after the other. Then people become more
and more detached from their culture
because 20 years ago 25 years ago years
ago your parents also went to this
rotten education system. They also spent
hours every day
embibing knowledge from compromised
teachers and compromised textbooks.
And our textbooks and our teachers don't
teach you about your culture about our
culture. So your parents
were detached from Indian culture to a
certain extent. Now they raised you
and they're already detached from
culture to let's say 30% detached. You
will be detached from c your culture
maybe 50%. There's going to be more
right and your kids will be detached
from the Indian culture by 70%.
Eventually after five six generations
more Indians will know nothing about
their culture. They will think of Indian
culture as the same way thing they think
of Egyptian culture or Greek culture or
Roman culture. That's what the Indian
education system is designed to do
generation after generation.
So yeah in 50 years 100 years you may no
longer have any anything called Indian
civilization. By the time India probably
you know will have converted to some
foreign religions. Most of most of the
Indians it's already happening you know
large scale uh industrial scale
demographic re-engineering projects are
going on in India
right as part of Indian democracy
apparently
a civil war I don't know about that but
yeah okay
v says interesting numbers US total
senates 100 you mean senators 100 nine
are Jewish 85 are Christian yet
pro-Israel votes 85% plus AIPAC backed
uh 361 out of 468 candidates in 2024.
How many senators do you have in the US?
It's a 100. Okay. So there are 100
senators in the United States Senate.
So each state throws up two senators.
Okay.
So I will not ask the Google AI to look
into the religious demographics and
pro-Israel votes because that will be
controversial for the AI. It'll flag me.
So let's not do that. But interesting.
So AIPAC backed 361 out of 468
candidates in 2024. So the majority of
candidates whichever way were backed by
this thing called AIPAC. What is AIPAC?
On second let's find out.
AIPAC.
What is that? American Israel Public
Affairs Committee. It's a bipartisan
lobbying group. So, it doesn't matter
whether it's Republicans or Democrats
that they're supporting. Bipartisan,
influential American US lobbying group
that advocates for strong USIsrael
relations. Founded in 1954, it works to
secure US security assistance, promote
diplomatic ties, and influence federal
elections to elect pro-Israel candidates
from both parties. So when you have
a lobbying group that works to influence
federal elections and it has strong ties
to a foreign nation, would you not
consider that to be foreign interference
in your electoral process?
Or maybe not. Maybe I'm too stupid to
see it that way. Or maybe I'm stupid to
see it that way. I don't I don't know
what it is.
So if you had a lobbying group in India
with very strong connections to a
foreign country and their job would be
was to influence elections in India, I
would see it as interference in my
nation's internal affairs.
That that's logic, right? Yeah. Okay. So
interesting. Interesting indeed.
Uh Harsh Raj says do you have any
part-time job for students? Um no I
don't. Um
I do not have a part-time job for
students. Yeah, I can't think of
anything. If if if I if I need
something, I will post it on um on the
community posts page. But right now, I
don't have any part-time job for
anybody. Yeah. Okay,
DJ says karma is a FIFO Q CS first in
first out Q computer science concept.
Okay, first in first out Q. Is it like
that?
Could be perhaps I'll have to think
about that. That's an interesting way of
looking at it. Yeah, first in first out
Q
or is it the cumulative merits and
demerits of your actions
or does it follow a sequential order?
I'm not sure about that, but it's a
really interesting way of looking at
things. Yeah. Okay. JRXNA
says, "Some countries have only a few
weeks of oil left now that a ground
invasion is likely. Won't this delay
hormone opening? How will these
countries react? How can they join the
war without oil reserves?"
Yes. So, uh see Hormos, the state of
Hormos is controlled by Iran now. They
have never closed the straight of
hormones in the past. Never once. This
is the first time in history that the
Iranians have closed the straight of
Hormos. And it's not closed completely.
It's closed to some nations
for shipments of oil that are destined
for India. It's open
right
for shipments of oil destined for or is
it completely closed right now? Let me
see.
Has Iran completely closed the straight
of Hormuz as of right now?
Uh, it is effectively closed to most
international shipping.
Uh, so forcing a 95% drop in traffic. Or
is this propaganda from the west?
Um, Iran is allowing select nonallied
vessels passage reportedly charging some
for tra for safe transit. They have
instituted a toll booth or shakedown
system. Oh, very nasty word to use
shakedown. What is what what is SW?
Isn't that also a shakedown system? What
is Panama? Isn't that a shakedown
system?
So, they're charging a toll. It's a
toll. It's not shakedown. So, they're
allowing some uh Asian flagged Chinese
and Indian tankers to pass while
blocking vessels linked to the US or
Israel.
Okay. So it's uh so so the Google AI is
is claiming that this uh straight is
about 95% closed and some vessels are
being allowed to to to transit if they
pay a toll. That's mainly Chinese and
Indian vessels apparently.
So that's the situation. Now some
countries obviously they're going to
have just a few weeks of oil left. Um
and those countries could import oil
from Russia.
But the Ukrainians are in the process of
destroying Russia's oil export
capabilities.
Ukraine
well it's at war with Russia so you
can't say it's doing something that's
very nasty but the timing is obviously
impeccable right the timing is it's
coinciding with what's happening in
Hormuz and Ukraine takes orders from the
US.
So that's what's happening. So yeah,
it's going to be a it's going to cause a
big oil crisis worldwide and then what
will happen is that the world will have
to buy oil from the US.
Can the US supply the world with oil?
We'll have to see about that. So a
ground invasion seems to be likely now
like you say. Correct. And will this not
delay the opening of the state of
Hormos? It certainly will delay the
opening of the straight of Hormos.
Absolutely. So how will these countries
react? These countries will have to find
some way. I think they will have to
import oil from the US, right? And can
they join the war in without oil
reserves? You can't fight a war if you
are taught on fuel, right? And it's not
like Venezuela wants to join the war.
It's not like Argentina wants to join
the war. It's not like South Africa
wants to join the war. Nobody wants to
join this war unless they are forced
into it by the Americans. Right? So
these nations will will have to look for
alternative sources of oil. I suppose
the Americans are a major oil producer.
Um, which are the major oil producing
nations? Let's find out.
U top 10 oil producing nations.
So the US, Saudi Arabia, the US is the
has the top position because of its high
shale oil production. Next is Saudi
Arabia. And then then you have Russia
up, Canada, China,
uh, and so on and so forth. Okay. Iraq,
UEI, Brazil,
Iran, Kuwait. Okay.
Um, so you can't join a war if you're
short on fuel.
And anyway, these most of the nations
they don't want to join this war. Yeah.
So they will have to buy oil maybe from
the US if the US is is capable of
supplying them with oil.
Yes. Praash says retired bodybuilder
for India.
Okay. Retired bodybuilder from India.
Big fan. You help my students. You're
very welcome indeed. Yeshuan G. Let me
Google you. Let's see. Yeshuan Praash.
Retired bodybuilder.
Ah. Oh, you're from the UK. Are you
okay? Okay. Okay. Okay. Fantastic. Let's
see.
That is Mr. Yeshu Praash.
Outstanding. Outstanding.
Thank you so much for being a viewer
sir. Thank you so much for being a
viewer and you are very welcome indeed.
V says Mir Shimemer argued that dip
state deep state deep state was against
the U the Iran war. Obama hated
Netanyahu. Yes. Biden Trump won were
cautious. Vitkov Kushner lobby convinced
Trump for this blunder.
Well, that's a theory. Now, we don't
know what really happened, but it could
be a plausible theory. Vitkov and
Kushner, the lobby, the the Israel
lobby, they convinced Trump to launch
this war on Iran. Well, I think that's
that's a plausible theory.
Logically, if it can make sense, yeah,
but is that what really happened? We
don't know about that. I mean, at least
I don't know what really happened. So,
it's it's a good theoretical framework
to understand what could have caused the
war. It's a I think it's it's a good
logically sound theory, but I don't know
if it's true. There are other theories
as well that you know could also make
sense. But, okay. Yeah. Right. And John
Mir Shimemer is the author of a book
about the Israel lobby in the US. So if
he has authored that book about the
Israel lobby in the US, he's going to
put forth theories that that that that
are in line with um the premise of his
book. So yeah, makes sense.
Uh Kits says EU quietly aids US attacks
on Iran, impact on EU. See, uh
we know that there are some u there are
there is at least one um British air
force base that's being used by the US
um to launch strikes on Iran
or at least it's part of the chain, you
know, the chain of
it's part of the chain of strikes.
Uh about the EU, I suppose the EU is
also possibly involved in some way or
the other. of some shape or form. Uh but
it's uh if if EU nations are indeed
helping in that case they're doing it
quietly like you say quietly aids.
Uh so if it's done quietly it's not very
obvious then I suppose there will be no
immediate impact on these nations. If
the aid they are providing to the US is
very open, very blatant and uh blatant
and its effects are directly
you know visible then I suppose Iran
could take some action against those
nations. See Iran has besa can reach all
almost all parts of the EU.
So Iran potentially could take some
action if they if they decide to. But
right now it doesn't look like there
will be any significant impact on the EU
at this point in time or in the
foreseeable near future. Near future
Tresler says US being so powerful why
lost war in Vietnam, Afghanistan, etc.
Okay, see
the Vietnamese understood how to fight
the Americans, right? The Americans were
far from their territory.
Um, and they mis like George W. Bush
would say they misunderestimated the
Vietnamese.
Um, the Vietnamese knew their terrain,
they knew their climate, they were great
at jungle warfare, they were adept
at Ma's people's war tactics
and they were determined. They were
fighting for the existence and survival
of their homeland. The American soldiers
were fighting because somebody told them
to fight. So it was also a question of
of motivation and determination, right?
and the Vietnamese so so because of way
these factors and because of uh the
excellence of Vietnam's gorilla not
gorilla guerrilla tactics etc that's why
uh they won the war and the Americans
eventually had to had to limp away from
Vietnam when it comes to Afghanistan
Afghanistan is is a very mountainous
country and uh the Afghanist the Afghan
resistance fighters they simply
outlasted the US And the US did not
really want it looks like to fully
occupy and govern Afghanistan.
The best of times the Americans were in
position were in actual control of only
a small portion of Afghanistan's
territory. And in various other parts of
Afghanistan, it was various resistance
groups that were in control of the
territory. The Americans tried their
best to to
defeat the resistance fighters whether
it is the Taliban, whether it is other
mujahedines,
but they because of the terrain
and because of various limitations and
constraints, the Americans were never
able to do this. you would need u an
invading uh invasion force of hundreds
of thousands of soldiers to effectively
take control of the entirety of of
Afghanistan.
So it simply would not work right. So
because of these limitations um the
Americans lost these wars. Um I suspect
the American objective was in
Afghanistan was never to really take
over the whole of Afghanistan and and
administer it. The objective was more of
money laundering and making money for
the for the military-industrial complex,
the big companies. Yeah, that's actually
what the mo most likely objective of the
Vietnam of the Afghanistan war was the
occupation of Afghanistan for 20 years.
So eventually the Americans ended up
replacing the Taliban with the Taliban.
Right? So it's not enough to be
powerful. You have to be determined. You
you have to know what your uh military
objectives are. You need to be very
clear about the military objectives. And
if your objective is to take control of
an entire nation, you have to put in the
resources for that. You have to be
prepared to go all in on that.
Not like I'll try something. If it
doesn't work out, I'll I'll send a few
more soldiers. If that doesn't work,
I'll send another 10,000 soldiers. And
keep sending more and more overtime
gradually. You have to go all in from
the beginning. And you can never ever
underestimate your opponent. So the US
obviously is a nation that suffers from
hubris and that's why the last time the
Americans wore a won a war on their own
single-handedly
was in 1898.
The Spanish US the Spanishame war.
That's the last time the Americans war
won a war on their own.
Okay. Aaron says, "Would we have
survived without the partition with a
third of the population being Muslim?
How could we implement no Sharia law
like what Turkey did? All it would take.
Of course, we could have survived
without a partition with a third of the
population being Muslim. Of course, we
could have. Right now in India, what's
the population of Muslims? Maybe maybe
20%. The last census was done in 2011,
right? Uh let's see
what percentage of India's population is
Muslim as per the 2011 census.
So per 2011 it was 14 or 14%. So today
it's 2026. It's been 15 years since the
last census. I have no idea why the
government has not done a census. I
understand there was a um the corona
virus uh thing pandemic but that ended
long ago. I have no idea why the
government has not done a census you
know. So uh in 15 years I suppose the
the the Muslim population may be close
to 20%. With all the tens of millions of
Bangladeshes in India, I'm sure the
Muslim population is more than 20% in
India. So we are doing fine with 20%
Muslims. It's not like Muslims are
problematic, right? It's not the case.
Okay.
So
um India would have done just fine
without a partition even with 33% of the
population being Muslim. All we needed
was the right leadership strong
leadership. If Subashundra Bose was the
leader of India was the dictator of
India he would have tolerated no
communal no religious BS he would have
tolerated none of that. He would have
crushed any such nonsense with an iron
fist. Okay.
Would have worked. Subhashundra Bose
would never have tolerated partition and
he would never have tolerated criminal
divisions and religious divisions.
They would have crushed it all. Of
course, they would have survived without
partition.
Omnak says your view on yoga cycles any
scientific parallel
uh the yoga cycles kal yoga dhpad yog
etc. Uh is there any scientific parallel
to that? Not that I know of. Not that I
know of. I'm not aware of any scientific
parallels to that.
Kub Chob, thank you very much Sergi.
Thank you very much.
An Divu says 1947 balkcanization follow
up. What was the geographical
geopolitical significance of cutting off
Burma and Bangladesh? See 1947 it was
not Bangladesh, it was East Pakistan,
right?
Uh so the objective was to give away as
much of the subcontinent territory to a
non-Indian nation as much of it as
possible.
See Bangladesh it's obviously
historically part of Bengal. It's a very
resourcerich
region,
right? The the Ganga River flows through
the through this region and flows into
the uh Indian Ocean, the Bay of Bengal,
the subset of the Indian Ocean and all
the all the all the aluvial deposits of
the Ganga River, they make this region
incredibly fertile. The Ganga delta,
right? They call it the Podma in the
region. But yeah, so it was very
significantly you know resourceri this
region. So cut off that region from
India and create this far east region
that you call the northeast but don't
give it access to the ocean by cutting
off by by giving chutagong to Burma uh
to to Bangladesh or to East Pakistan
sorry
and Burma
the objective was to make India small
right Burma was this big big if you look
at the map we haven't opened the map
today have we terrible let's open the
So Burma is a huge territory again very
resourcerich
very resourcerich and Burma was cut away
from India in 1935
Myanmar it's a huge huge country very
large okay and as you can see it it has
a very large border with with uh with
China and uh it's part of Southeast Asia
so India would have you know Indian
territory would have in Southeast Asia
as well if Burma had remained part of
India and it goes all the way down
south. So we would have been neighbors
with Thailand with Laos and with China,
Thailand, Laos and and China. We would
have been neighbors with these countries
directly. Right now Thailand is a
maritime neighbor of India. See as you
know we have Fuket, we have Phuket is
about a thousand kilometers roughly I
would say from uh Indian territory.
roughly 1,000 kilometers.
Let's see here. Okay, it's it's 500
something kilometers from Indian
territory. So, Thailand is a maritime
neighbor of India. Indonesia is also a
maritime neighbor of India. We don't
realize that. Okay. Uh so, this huge
territory was carved away from India. In
1935, there was an election in Burma and
Burma had voted to remain part of India.
But the British still nevertheless
disregarded the sentiments of the
Burmese people and carved Burma out of
India. Right? So if so the geopolitical
significance is is to weaken India. If
India if Burma was part of Indian
territory then we would have access to
significant parts of central of of
Southeast Asia. we would have been
neighbors with Laos and and Thailand and
with with more regions of China and we
would have access to all the resources
that you have in Burma. So we have been
cut off from that as well. So the
objective was to
of of the of the balkcanization of in
1947 one objective was to ensure India
remains weak.
Okay. India is deprived of its
historical access to these territories
like Southeast Asia, like Central Asia.
Okay. Um and the second objective was to
create this this artificial temporary
mercenary garrison state nation
Pakistan, East and West Pakistan, right?
Uh so that was what was it and obviously
they they ensured that not only is is
India balconized and east and west
Pakistan created and before that in 1935
Burma was chopped out of India but in
1947 they ensured that their hand
handpicked individuals became the the
political elite of India and they were
handpicked in such a way for the purpose
of keeping India weak right so they
ensure that India doesn't start growing
rapidly. Once the British leave, they
ensure that the entire edifice,
all the institutions the British had
created, those continued intact. Then
how have we acquired freedom if all the
same laws and all the same institutions
continue in place?
We may have technically become free, but
we never decolonized.
Right. Right. Okay.
Vive says, "Please help. My brother left
school in the 10th standard despite good
in social science, chess, poor at maths,
says the education system is garbage.
Wants to drive trucks in Australia."
Okay.
Um I
is it a bad thing to drive trucks in
Australia?
I I would say let every person decide
what is best for them in their life.
I I'm wondering if is driving trucks in
Australia a bad thing.
If somebody likes that, you want to
drive around the outback and whatever.
It's a nice adventurous life. I suppose
the pay is good.
I
I don't think it's it's a failure in
life.
And you can do that for four, five
years, 10 years. Then you can go back to
education and maybe become a chartered
accountant or something
or maybe become government servant.
Everything is possible in life.
So um I I I suspect I'm not giving you
the help you're looking for.
So what you could do? Okay. So that
that's one option. The other option is
you know what the education system is
garbage. I agree. I I'm I am responsible
for for making people aware of that.
But what you could say to your brother
is consider various options. Let's not
jump the gun immediately. One option is
you go to Australia, drive trucks. Okay.
Another option is you spend some more
years in the education system and maybe
if you have some other hopes and dreams,
maybe getting a degree could help you
achieve that.
Um that's also a possibility. So, so my
point is don't make take a decision
immediately.
Spend let's say give yourself four weeks
to decide and consider all the options.
One option, option A is Australia and
you drive trucks in the outback. Option
B is maybe you continue with the
education system for another another
five years
and acquire a degree and maybe if you
have some dream some hope that you may
actually that you wanted to become let's
say an airline pilot for example or
let's say you wanted to drive tanks in
the in the Indian army
or maybe you wanted to become um a
chartered accountant in India. So those
options are also there and there are
other ways of reaching those options. So
at the end of the day it'll decide it
will depend on what the what your
brother wants the most in his life
right. So I would say so sometimes you
take decisions emotionally right
sometimes you want to go and beat up the
guy you don't like. So what what you're
supposed to say is okay listen we'll
beat him but let's beat him tomorrow.
Not right now. Sleep on it. So I would
say tell your brother to to think about
this for a while. Don't decide
immediately. Take take let's say a month
to decide then you can still go and do
what you want but take a month to decide
and consider all the options. So maybe
that will help. All right Vive all the
best and say hi to your brother.
Anabilar says I believe
is big. What's
I believe is a bigger enemy than China.
Your thoughts? I suspect you're saying
US.
Well, as India's unofficial
representative to the world, I will say
that let's be diplomatic about this. The
US, our relationship with the US is
challenging.
We allegedly have shared values with
them, but clearly we don't have too many
shared interests with them.
And actually if you look at the matter
civilizationally
we have way more shared values with
Chinese civilization than with the US
empire.
Right? And China obviously is a is a
real and present danger for India
because of the way it has behaved
since Mahatong took took control of of
of the country 1949 right was it right
they have behaved as an imperialistic
nation as a hedge they are very
hegemonic and they bully all their
neighbors that's why China is obviously
a problem for India but it's not like
the US isn't like that the US is it
takes that to the next level the US is
like 10 times times China when it comes
to its imperialistic practices,
its regime, it's meddling in every
country.
So I would say both nations are major
challenges for us. Which is larger,
which is less large?
I think the US is more of a challenge
for India.
Dir Kh says Google AI cloud and GPT
are better than Grock. Okay. Okay. So Dj
Kamat is of the opinion that Google AI
claw and GPT are better than Grock and
I'm doing good by using See my objective
first of all is never to use AI. I
simply look this is not the first
episode of the Askab show. This is the
344th episode of the Askab show. I have
been using Google as a search engine
since episode 1 probably since episode
1. I don't remember what happened in
episode 1 but from the beginning I've
been using Google uh to clarify things.
And when I started at the ask show,
there was no there was no AI, right? At
least not that I knew of. But now when I
do the same Google searches that I was
doing 4 years ago, now you have AI
generated, you know, synthesis of uh or
summaries.
So it's it's something that I've started
using unwittingly.
I have
always been using Google search, not
Google AI. AI then eventually started
intruding into my Google searches. So I
have become an unwitting user of Google
AI during the ask show. It's never been
my intention to do it and clearly it's
uh it's not always reliable as we
discovered yesterday very clearly when
it it was repeatedly lying about how
India voted in that UN resolution about
the transatlantic slaves slave trade.
The Google AI kept saying that India had
abstained when actually India had voted
in favor of the resolution. So clearly
AI is not necessarily going to be 100%
reliable and that's something we have to
be very very aware of. So I have become
unfortunately an unwitting user of
Google AI or whatever AI. Uh my my
intention is never to use AI. My
intention is to just do Google searches.
But yeah uh so you are saying that
Google AI and cloud and GPD are better
than Grock. So I've used Google AI GPD
everyone has used Grock I haven't really
used much so I don't know how good it
may be uh Elon Musk obviously will claim
it's the best in the world but hey
so okay so one my point is one has to be
careful with AI don't ever
you know take what AI says as the gospel
truth very dangerous to do that AI
you know can can be misleading.
Jagara says, "What happened to your
right eye? Are you okay? Did you cry or
sad?" So, this is my right eye. What
happened to it? What happened? Let's
Let's take a closer look, shall we?
Let's zoom in. So, here's my right eye.
What happened to it?
I have no idea what happened to it. My
The right eye is completely fine.
Completely fine. Did I cry? Am I sad?
Uh, and Golibar says, "See a doctor
ASAP. Your right eye looks odd. Not
sleeping." What?
What happened to my right eye? I I I
wonder has something happened to it?
Let's see. I think it looks fine.
I don't see any problems. So as far as
I'm concerned, I have not seen anything
wrong with my eye, right eye. It's
I'm able to see just fine with it. Uh
did you see something? Did you notice
something? I even yesterday somebody
asked me asked me about my right eye.
Am I turning into a werewolf or a
vampire or something? I don't know.
Look, I really appreciate the concern. I
don't see anything wrong with my right
eye. It's functioning perfectly fine. I
am um I didn't cry. I'm not sad. I am
sleeping just fine.
Uh but yeah, after this show this
episode is over, I'll go and check it
out in the in in the mirror and I'll
have somebody check it for me and uh if
there is an issue, I'll get it addressed
at the earliest. All right. Thank you.
Aon says, "Aon aon d nice dice." Aon
Timoth
yeah
key and peel of course. So Aeron says
should we blame the illiterate polit
politicians in power or bureaucrats for
ruining our country awful education
system the system being corrupt as a
whole.
So it's a chicken and egg and egg
problem. Who is what is the problem? Is
it the system that's the problem or is
it the politicians and bureaucrats
that's the problem? Because a system is
made up of the politicians and
bureaucrats.
It's it's a self-perpetuating system
cycle, isn't it? So look, this system
was created by the British and they
deliberately designed it in to be such
that it oppresses the people.
It would serve the British and at the
same time it would oppress the people.
That's how they designed the system.
They designed the corruption as a
feature not as a bug.
Okay, it was designed into the system.
It was a feature not a bug. And after
1947, the system has continued exactly
the same without anything being changed.
Maybe uh if no um IC became IAS. So they
changed some titles from the even Indian
civil services to the Indian
administrative services and some things
gradually changed but overall the system
remained the same right so whatever
features the British had introduced into
the system they had designed into the
system those still continue
and that's why the system only accepts
certain kinds of people the the other
kinds of people are shoved away
and even if you come in with the best of
intentions once you see how the system
works you have no choice but to become
part of the system or move out.
Okay. So you so so
somebody will have to you can't reform
the system. You have to dismantle the
system and replace with a new one. It's
very hard to to change the system from
inside. It has be it has to be changed
from outside. And that's
next to impossible in the current scheme
of things. So who do we blame for this?
I would say the people who should be
blamed primarily are those who after
1947 did not change the system. They
simply continued it.
They you blame them because they are
deserving of the blame.
Um
and
well who else do you blame? The top
leadership I suppose at various points
in time in Indian history since 1947.
Aniket says why nose and ears never stop
growing? Um
why do the nose and ears never stop
growing? I I don't know. I've never
thought about that. I don't know.
Okay. Secondly, your podcast with Major
General Rajiv Narayan was great and his
insights especially about Nav'i were
solely Singh.
Okay. First of all, thank you about uh
the I'm glad that you like the podcast.
Now about Navik,
I did not wish to argue with the
general.
So I did not.
He said there are 8 nine satellites and
so on right that are functional
including LEO satellites low
low earth observational satellites low
earth orbit satellites LU see if you
want Navic to be functional
you need at least four functional
satellites that are in geostationary
orbit
geostationary orbit is roughly 36,000 km
above the planet surface let's let's
fact check that okay uh I'm obviously
saying This is from memory. Maybe my
memory is wrong. Let's ask uh Google.
At what altitude are geostationary
satellites positioned?
36,000 km roughly. Yeah, roughly 36,000
km. Okay. So geostation for Navik to be
operational you need at least four
functional satellites to be placed in
geostationary orbits.
Okay.
Now General Narayan was saying that we
have 8 nine satellites that are
functional. He was including low earth
orbit satellites.
Low earth orbit satellites cannot be
part of NAVIK. NAVIK is a satellite
positioning system.
Low earth orbit satellites are spy
satellites.
They will give you high resolution
images
of the earth's surface and other data.
High resolution data from close to the
earth's surface. Low earth orbit
satellites are typically between 200
around 200 300 kilometers above the
surface.
not 36,000 km very close to the surface.
The atmosphere ends at about let's say
100 km and these satellites are about
200 or 300 km above the surface. So
that's the 8 n
see total he is saying there are 89
satellites of which there are three
navic which are still somewhat
functional and maybe five six low earth
orbit satellites. You put that together
it does not give you a functional navic
system.
Our navikism is no longer functional.
It's it's not functional anymore.
Okay, that is the truth.
We have only at most three functional
Navic satellites. At most, maybe even
not three.
And that is not sufficient to give you
satellite satellite positioning data.
So if you try to you know uh
find an information find find your
location specific exact location the
coordinates using Navic with your phone
right now it's not going to give you an
accurate uh fix on your location. It's
not going to do that. Navic is no longer
functional. Okay we have messed up with
Navic. those those other low earth
satellites those are those are military
spy satellites then we don't talk about
them but they don't give you the
positioning fix that Navik is supposed
to give you so
is not real solace I did not want to
argue with the esteemed
general Narayan that's why I did not say
after anything after that but Navic is
not functional it's
those spy those those spy satellites are
a whole different matter. Okay, it's
like comparing
u
huge
it's like comparing those huge uh
transport aircraft with the theasis
fighter jet. You can't compare. Those
are totally different rules. It's like
comparing a helicopter
with a submarine.
There's no comparison. Right. Right.
Hershu Jane says, "I don't think Kirk
Island is the target because everyone
knows it's 100% suicidal. Do you think
all this drama is for something totally
different that will catch all of us offg
guard? What can it be?" So, I discussed
this yesterday. So, I agree with you.
Kirk Island doesn't seem to be the right
target. Let's let's uh let's look at the
map and understand why Kirk Island is
suicidal.
So, where is Kir Island? Okay, so here
we are off the coast of western India.
Let's go westwards into the Gulf of
Oman. Let's go into the straight of
Hormos. Let's transition into the
Persian Gulf. Let's go past Qatar. Let's
go past Bushar. Let's go close to
Kuwait. And here we have Ka Island.
Okay, this one here, if you look at the
satellite imagery, you will see it's got
all these oil storage facilities and so
on, right?
oil boulevard and oil storage facilities
etc. What is that fountain?
Netorian. What's it look like? Okay. So
that that's okay. So Kirk Island is
about what 35ish kilometers from from um
the coastline of Iran. 30-ish
kilometers. Right now, if the Americans
try to take this island, they will have
to send an amphibious assault vehicle
ship of some kind like the Tripoli,
which will have to sail through the
through the straight of Hormuz. If it
tries to stay sail through the straight
of Hormuz, it's going to be obliterated
by Iranian drones and missiles. It is
guaranteed to be completely destroyed.
Guaranteed. 100% guaranteed. Because the
Iranians have so many drones and
missiles, the Americans simply won't be
able to survive this. So the question is
if they try to come here they'll be
destroyed. Then how will they reach Kar
island? They can't. Another option is
they perhaps land somewhere in Saudi
Arabia or Kuwait and then perhaps take
helicopters to parachute over there or
something. But even that is suicidal
because the Iranians will shoot down
their helicopters. Or maybe it takes
some boat or ship to reach there. How do
they do it? So that's why reaching Kirk
is almost impossible. And even if they
are able to reach K and they are able to
take Kirk hypothetically, how long will
they survive there?
Because when you do an amphibious
amphibious assault on a place, you come
with maybe one day of water and food,
not more per soldier. So how do you
survive there? And if you take Kirk
Island, they want the Iranians
completely flatten the island with their
missiles and drones. Nothing will
nothing, nobody will survive. Which is
why I agree with Harshett that Kirk
cannot be the target. It's suicidal.
100% suicidal guaranteed. So what could
be the actual target in that case? If
the USS Tripoli like the Americans are
claiming has reached the Sentcom area of
operations, then it's somewhere here.
It's somewhere here in the so-called
Arabian Sea or the Gulf of Adan,
the Red Sea, I don't know, the Gulf of
Moan somewhere. So I would say that it
is more probable that they will try to
make a move on Shabahar
or Kodarak.
Kodarak here or Chabahar here. Where is
Chabahar?
This is Chabahar.
I think that's more likely and they
could even have support from Pakistan
because the Pakistani border isn't
really far away from Chabahar, right?
100 km away is Pakistan. So the
Americans could make a move on Shabahar
potentially with support from Pakistan
which means Pakistan gets directly
involved for the first time that I think
is more likely than the Americans trying
to take uh KUR in a suicidal operation.
If they take Chabahar they could they
may be able to potentially sustain their
occupation of Chabahar with Pakistani
help
right and then I suppose Trump could
claim victory of some kind. I don't know
because even if they take Jabahar they
don't have they haven't defeated Iran.
They haven't defeated Iran but u I don't
know maybe it's some kind of empty
hollow victory that they want. So I
think u that you know Kirk Island seems
to be out of the question. It's it's
impossible to take and it's suicidal to
take and it's suicidal to defend.
Right.
So I think Chawahar makes more sense and
obviously the Iranians aren't stupid.
They will be thinking thinking along
those lines too. They will be thinking
of all potential scenarios of what the
Americans could try to take and um you
know try to take an occupy from the
Iranians. So I think it could be
Chabahar. I think it could be Chabahar.
Let's wait and watch.
Okay. 24 Bat says the RA lady is silly.
Uh Madame Nirup Minra. Okay. If India
lectures the US, the US will stop war. I
mean that's what she seems to imagine.
Or maybe she thinks that whether the US
stops the war or not, India should
lecture the world and India should
lecture the US. That way we absolve
ourselves morally that we have done our
duty and lectured the Americans because
our duty is to lecture. That's what she
seems to think and that's that's what
she's recommending that we should
lecture the Americans.
Staying weak and verbal lectures are
over. I completely agree with you. It's
high time we move past that and we have
moved past that.
Okay. Everything we do should advance
our interests. Everything. Even if it is
a statement, that statement should
advance our interests. Don't do anything
that doesn't serve our interests. So why
should we make these moralizing
lectures? Why? Right. So what you're
saying is that only action, growth, and
strength can defeat imperialism.
Completely agree with you. I could not
dis I could not agree more. I could not
agree more. Agree more. Absolutely
correct.
Yes,
Kiki Susant says, "Thank you, sir." Oh,
thank you. Thank you so much. You You
are very welcome and thank you very
much.
Harsh Jin says, "Trump has already said
that Cuba is next. Do you think Russia
will proactively protect Cuba more than
it's helping Iran?" No, I don't think
so. Why do I say I don't think so? Why
do I not think so? Well, ask yourselves,
what did Russia do when the Americans
took over
Venezuela?
They didn't physically take out
Venezuela, but they kidnapped Maduro and
installed
a government which was already there,
but they ensured that the government
flipped and became pro-American. And now
the government of Venezuela does
whatever the Americans want them to do.
So when the Americans did this, did this
regime change, de facto regime change,
what did the Russians do? They did
nothing, right? Russia did not do a
thing to help Venezuela. Or did they?
The Russians had supplied Venezuela with
air defense systems. They had supplied
Venezuela with potentially intelligence.
The Russians had done whatever they
could to help Venezuela. But Venezuela
the the the the
leadership they decided that let's give
up Madur to the Americans and then yeah,
let's become American an American vasal.
So Russia is physically very far away
from Venezuela. Once again, let's go to
the map and let's find out.
Okay. So where is Venezuela? Venezuela
is here. How far is it from Russia?
Okay. Let's let's try and calculate the
distance from Russia.
So Venezuela,
we measure the distance to let's say
um here that's about 10,000 kilometers.
Russia is roughly 10,000 kilometers away
from Venezuela. What can it do to help?
It can't do much if the Americans
invade. And similarly, Cuba must be
about more than 10,000 km. 1 second for
Cuba. How far is Russia?
Let's go and measure the same distance.
It's more than 10,000 km. So, Russia
can't do much. Russia doesn't have any
power projection capabilities in this
region. Russia doesn't have any military
bases in this region. Right? So, Russia
can't do much to help them.
Um, that is the situation. So, if Trump
makes a move on on Cuba, there's nothing
the Russians can do to help Cuba. Cuba
is a setting duck right now. Okay, that
is it.
Okay. Rahul says, "I have a promising
transformer architecture improvement for
top computer science conference like
ICRL, ICML, New IPS, but no GPUs to
train or test it. Any suggestions?"
Well,
what suggestions can I give you? You
have to acquire GPUs.
Can you hire GPUs? Can you
I I'm not sure. I've never thought of
this problem because I'm not into this
into this field.
Can you I mean ideally you should have
your own GPUs
but can you rent GPUs by the hour or
something? Is that possible?
Let me um
ask Google.
Can you rent GPU clusters by the hour?
Let's see. Yes, you can rent GPU
clusters on individual GPU instances by
the hour. Numerous cloud providers offer
on demand, hourly, even per second
billing for high performance GPUs,
allowing you to scale from a single card
to large clusters for AI training and
inter in inference without long-term
commitments.
So multi-node clusters you can rent
multiple interconnected GPUs for
distributed trading workloads scaling up
to 10,000 plus G,000 plus GPUs in some
cases.
Um
Jarvis Labs offers Nvidia A10 800 and
H100 GPUs starting from about 40 cents
per hour to 269 per hour. And obviously
this is going to be expensive.
The the costs add up rapidly.
Yeah. So I suppose you can rent GPUs but
the costs will add up very rapidly. You
can buy GPUs. GPUs are very expensive.
Uh so uh if you are in a university or
college I suppose you could ask your
department to acquire this in case they
think that you know you should do
sovereign AI research in India.
Otherwise you'll have to somehow find
the funds to do it. Right? That's all I
can say.
Um yeah so these are the these are the
problems Indian researchers face
mainly the shortage of funds
so um that's what I can say if you are
in a in a college department or
university department ask your
department request your department to
supply you the funds or to simply buy
the hardware themselves and then you can
you know set it up and use it and you
can say it's not mine it's it's it's
going to be it's going to belong to the
department and you can do future
research on that. That's one thing you
do
or otherwise uh you find some source of
funds and acquire it. All right, sir.
All the best. Yeah, I I understand how
these these constraints can be real
problematic but yeah. Okay. All the best
sir. All the best. Rahul
WBKT says is it safe to say that India
cannot dismantle Pakistan until the US
decides your opinion on Jeffrey Saks
also even MAGA people are critical of
the attack on the girls school is it
safe to say that India cannot dismantle
Pakistan until the US agrees to this
yeah as long as the US has its
gives it its blessings to Pakistan India
can't do a
So India will be able to dismantle
Pakistan only after the US loses
interest in Pakistan and if China
doesn't come in and you know take over
the role of the US as long as there's a
more powerful nation than India who is
protecting Pakistan we can't do much
until unless we want to risk a major war
that could be against more than one
nation.
My opinion on Jeffrey Sax. Who is
Jeffrey Sax? I'm not sure. Let me check
out who is Jeffrey Sak. I'm sure I know
who it is, but let me see. Jeffrey Sak.
Yeah, American economist and public
policy analyst, professor at Columbia
University. I do recognize this
gentleman's face. I am not aware of what
he has been speaking about. So, I don't
have much of an opinion about him. What
his positions are. Is he does he uh what
does he do? geopolitical analysis,
international affairs analysis, economic
analysis. I'm not sure, I am not aware
of what he has been saying. So I don't
have much of an opinion about him and
even MAGA people are critical of the
attack on girls school. I think any sane
any decent human being will be critical
of the of the horrific attack on the
school the the the girls school in in in
Iran. How many girls died? How many kids
died? Definitely more than 100. more
than 150. So any any any sane decent
human being will will be critical of
that. Nobody can support that sort of
horrific atrocity.
Hyphen says if the US pressures India to
align more strongly, can India
realistically resist without economic or
geopolitical consequences?
I suppose we can. Right now India is
aligning away from the US not completely
but uh like we discussed yesterday
India has gone ahead with uh deals with
Russia worth about cumulatively $25
billion. We're going to be purchasing
drones. We're going to be purchasing
missiles. We're going to be purchasing
uh transport aircraft. We're going to be
doing nuclear cooperation with the
Russians and and and other things as
well.
And that's something that's and of
course of S400 systems we're purchasing
more of those. This is going to
displease the US very very greatly.
Right? So we are clearly resisting
American
uh pressures. Clearly we are resisting.
The US is of course pressurizing India
right now to align very strongly with
them. The US wants India as a vasal
state. It's very clear. They have made
it very clear and India is now taking
various uh steps that essentially are
taking India away from the alignment
with the US and more of a and and more
towards an alignment with Russia
at least some alignment with Russia
right and more than what we have been
doing in the past and now we are also
increasing our our our intake of Russian
oil
uh and this is Because as a consequence
of the past month of the Iran war, the
US its leverage over India has reduced.
The the the the standing and stature of
the US in the world has come down
several notches,
right? And India seems to have
calculated that it now has more leverage
than the US or at least the balance is
is is is better now. Uh, of course
there's going to be consequences. The US
will will take some steps eventually.
Maybe more tariffs, maybe something or
the other. We'll see about that.
Tariffs, sanctions, something. But of
course, you know, you there's always a
price you to pay for sovereignty when
you are not the most powerful nation in
the world. Yeah.
Stick life says, "Do you think that the
US and Israel have achieved their key
goal of stopping Iran from getting
nuclear weapons?" Thanks for the great
content. Love you. Thank you so much.
Thank you so much indeed. So the
question really is what was their key
goal? What was the objective of the US
and what was the objective of Israel in
starting this war? The Americans say
that we want our objective is
um the opening of the straight of Hormuz
and Iranian guarantees that they will
not uh you know uh develop nuclear
weapons. Well, before the war started,
the state of Hormos was already open and
Iran already had committed to not
developing nuclear weapons. So the US
already had that and they still started
the war and now they are saying that we
want to achieve those things which
already had.
Iran had signed the GCPOA, the joint
comprehensive plan of action in 2016 or
whatever it was 2015 2016 around that
time and they had committed to not
enriching uranium beyond 60% and
whatever the commitments were. So the
and this was all verified by the IAEA,
the International Atomic Energy um
whatever it is IAEA,
International Atomic Energy Association
or a agency agency, right? They their
inspectors had come and and inspected
all the Iranian facilities and they
found that Iran was complying with this
and even until February 2026 before the
war began, Iran was not deploy
developing nuclear weapons. The supreme
leader of Iran had imposed a fatwa
against nuclear weapons. So Iran was
definitely not deploy developing nuclear
weapons and Iran had not closed the
straight of Hormos.
The Americans already had those
conditions. Then they launched the war
and now they want they said that these
are all goals. So why did you start the
war? You already had those conditions.
Uh so I'm not sure what the objectives
of the war for the US are right now. I
have no idea.
They don't seem to have clear
objectives. The objectives have kept
kept changing. For Israel, they want to
do regime change. nothing less than
regime change will will be sufficient
for Netanyahu and for for Israel. So
Israel has not achieved its goal
and now it makes sense for Iran to
develop nuclear weapons. It makes sense
for Iran to develop nuclear weapons.
That just makes sense logically because
without that there's no guarantee that
you know if even if the war ends at some
time point in time it won't resume in a
couple of years. So maybe the war ends
hypothetically now. Okay, let's say
hypothetically the war ends now and the
US and Israel say okay okay we are done
with the war we will not fight anymore
let's have a ceasefire and all three
sides say okay it's a ceasefire what's
going to prevent the Americans and
Israelis from regrouping
taking a couple of years to rebuild
their their arsenal and then attacking
Iran again in two years what's going to
stop them from doing it the only thing
that can stop them is if Iran develops
nuclear weapons so I think now Iran will
develop nuclear weapons and they're not
going to clo open the state of H
foremost anytime soon. Um so I don't
think the Americans have achieved any of
their military objectives. I don't think
Israel has achieved its political
objectives, military objectives.
So yeah, I don't see this war ending
anytime soon.
Yeah. Okay.
Uh 24 BAT says M.
No comments. No comments.
Hey, listen. No comments. No comments.
Okay. Wy BKT says, "Did you saw tweet by
by somebody called Bhar Mudan
whitewashing arrest of US and Ukrainian
nationals claims that even Great Britain
interfered in the US civil war but later
became allies. I have not seen this
tweet and um uh so
yeah I'm not aware of this.
I I will look into that later and let's
not call people names. Okay, let's be a
little more dignified.
What's the point of calling people
names? Let's not do that. Please,
please, let's maintain decorum on this
channel. All right, it's my request.
Please.
Okay.
Okay. Uh or should I look into that
later? Later. I'll look into it later.
Okay. Uh 24 Bat says, "Perplexity is
better than Grock. Sorry for making you
angry yesterday." Uh was I angry
yesterday? I may have been very briefly
slightly annoyed, but that's okay. I I I
it doesn't matter. It's fine. It's fine.
No issues. No. No issues whatsoever. So
you were saying that perplexity is
bedding rock. I see perplexity.
Perplexity is like a search engine on
steroids, right? An AI enabled or
something search engine.
So okay. So it's better I look into
perplexity also in that case. Do you all
think that it's better that I search on
on an AI system for information rather
than doing Google searches? Because
Google searches anyway come with with
its own Google AI thing, right?
I look into that. I look into that. But
anyway, thank you for the recommendation
for perplexity.
Better than Grock. Interesting. I
suppose Grock searches X, right? Grock,
I mean Grock owns I mean Elon Musk owns
Grock. He also owns owns X. So Grock, I
suppose, has been trained on the massive
volume of data that you have on X. and
Grock will be aware of everything that's
happening on X. So, who's saying what?
So, I suppose Grock would be a good
search engine for Twitter or X, but not
necessarily for other things. But I
suppose Perplexity is a global general
search engine and it uh pulls up results
from relevant uh parts of the internet
and then summarizes them properly. So, I
think yeah that that way should be
better. Interesting. Okay.
Okay. Okay. WBKT says, "Please see photo
of E3 sentry that got allegedly got
damaged." Well, I shall show you the
photo.
Yes, indeed. So, where is that?
Here we have it,
right? It's an Awax system.
Awax uh aircraft. So, here we have it.
Here we have it.
Uh what is this? This is something else.
Okay. So um this is the AVAC E3 AVAC
that was damaged damaged into quotes.
Do you call this damage? It's been
obliterated.
It's been destroyed. The aircraft is in
multiple pieces. And the most valuable
part of the aircraft which is the rad
is entirely obliterated. The rad is this
big big thing like a mushroom that's on
top of the aircraft. It's a gigantic
radar dome, right? And see what what's
happened is that the Iranians have
destroyed all the all the all the all
the powerful radars the Americans have
in the region. The THAD radars, which
are the terminal high altitude area
defense radars and other radars. These
radars cost like close to a billion
dollars a piece and there's only a few
of these radars in the world. The
Iranians have destroyed these radars and
that's why the Americans were using
these Awax aircraft to put radars in the
air to ensure that they they're still
able to see what the Iranians are doing,
what they're launching and what not. So
now three of these aircraft have been
destroyed or at least at least one of
these aircraft have been destroyed. And
the Americans only have 21 or so of
these aircraft, right? And this is not
damaged. This is obliterated. It's
destroyed. And the like like this tweet
says, the Iranians have targeted the key
rear housing surveillance radar, the big
radom on top of the on top of the
aircraft.
So yeah.
Yeah. So the Iranians are doing
rather superior job than the Americans
of targeting the enemy's u um assets and
infrastructure.
Okay.
Omniak says, "Can it be said that the US
doesn't have any selfidentity as a
civilizational nation? Every person
within leverage works for self-interest
or foreign interest. The US
is not a civilization.
The US is an empire.
You know what I say about Pakistan,
right? Pakistan is an artificial
temporary nation.
What is the US? It's an artificial
nation. It's a nation that's been
constructed on stolen territory.
It's a nation that is founded on
genocide and slavery.
The stolen territory belong to the
natives of the Americas.
Okay? And to justify the theft of the
territory, the Americans have invented
their own history of the Americas. And
in that in those histories, they portray
the natives as savages.
the savages with no culture with with no
society very backward primitive people
which makes sense that's why it makes
sense to take over the nation and
civilize the savages
so the US is an empire
it's not a civilization
what is American culture is there such a
thing as American culture
yeah
So um so the US it's an empire. It's not
a civilization. It doesn't really have a
culture of its own right and it's a out
andout capitalist nation. So yeah
everybody works for their own
self-interest and some people I suppose
potentially work for foreign interests.
So I cannot disagree with what you're
saying. I agree with you Omni. I agree.
Okay. Vijaya Patel says your views on
Sir Other Cotton and Andraas worship
him.
Sir Other Cotton.
What is Other Cotton?
Um let me try and Google this.
Author Cotton. Let's see. Sir Other
Cotton.
Oh, you mean Sir Arthur Cotton? Who is
this fellow?
He was a British army officer and
irrigation engineer who worked in the
Madras presidency.
And what did he do? He devoted his life
to the construction of irrigation and
navigation canals throughout British
India.
Well, if he did build canels, canels and
all that in India while he was
constructing the infrastructure of the
British occupation of India. Oh, sorry,
did I not? Sorry, I Okay, I need to put
this on the screen. Okay, so this guy
Arthur Cotton, he was a British army
officer and irrigation engineer who
worked in the Madras presidency. he uh
devoted his life to the construction of
irrigation and navigation canals canals
throughout British India. So if he was
constructing canals in British India, he
was constructing the infrastructure of
British occupation and extraction.
The infrastructure he was constructing
its objective what what was it being
going to be used for? It's going to be
it was going to be used for the British
occupation of India in the extraction of
India's resources out of India.
So that's what I can say. I don't know
this person. I've not studied this
person's life. I don't I was not aware
of his existence and he's just another
British occupier of India. Why do some
person people worship him if they do? I
wonder. But that's the problem with
India. You know our textbooks glorify
such people instead. They they really
did a great great job for India. They
served us. That's what we are taught.
That's why our people unwittingly start
worshiping them some of them if poss
potentially. Okay.
A Ron says, "Should we follow suit with
China and abandon religion altogether
instead of converting? No religion means
no cast reservations, no religion hatred
and hopefully more development." I
completely disagree with this. Why
should we abandon our religion? Why?
Why should we abandon our religion that
our ancestors followed for 10 for like
10,000 or more years? Why
we should abandon cast reservations
and religion? Our religion has never
stopped anybody from developing.
There is a phase of Indian history
called this araspati sindu phase or the
indust value or harpan phase. Right?
India was fully urbanized, fully
industrialized at the time and we were
still Hindus. Our religion does not
prevent us from us from developing. It
is not anti-development. It is some
other religions that are
anti-development by the way.
Okay. We should abandon cast
reservations. We should abandon cast.
Okay. Not abandon our culture and our
religion. Absolutely disagree with that.
Absolutely disagree with that. Why
should we make concessions? Why should
we make compromises
in our own land? Why? I don't get it. We
should not.
Vinodab says one day take a full history
session slides on Iranian history 920 to
2026 covering structure and key figures
like Sulmani Ayatah's lari
gi well Solmani larjani raj gi are very
recent history
I mean they are relevant today was was
assassinated a few years ago
okay you want me to do a whole thing on
Iranian history well the thing is that
Iranian history doesn't start in 1920
right but yeah of of course interesting
uh recommendation suggestion should I do
that would people be interested in that
I suppose I could do that it will take
me some time to prepare that but it's
not a bad suggestion
yeah it's not a bad suggestion let me
take a note of this let me take a
screenshot of this
u suggestion by way
here we have it and I'll save that. It's
not a bad suggestion at all. Well, thank
you VA for the suggestion. I will take
this up.
I am Duresh says, "Ever let go of an
opportunity to settle abroad. Why
have I ever let go of an opportunity to
settle abroad?" I'm sure I have. Why?
Because it felt like the right thing to
do, I suppose.
Yeah.
Soldier boy says, "What's your take on
FC? Did that please you?" Yes, I am
pleased. I'm pleased. It's good. Yes.
So, we are we are strengthening making
making the rules more stringent. Yeah.
See, FC is is the channel through which
foreign funds flow into India. And
there's a lot of misuse of FC. So the
new FC rules are going to be more
stringent and they're going to have more
conditions and they hopefully that leads
to improvements and uh you know that
sort of thing. So I think yeah overall
I'm pleased. Yes.
WBKT says UA. Why is it always UA? It
should be US, right?
Are you saying Ukraine?
Oh, UA is Ukraine. Is it UA is Ukraine?
It should be UK, right? No, it's UK is
UK UK R or it could be UK UA. Okay. So,
Ukraine had great industry like Antonov
but comedian messed it up. Yes.
Uh the Ukrainians had good good
industries, excellent industries,
aircraft industries and other things.
But today we have a comedian who's
running the running the show. Very
unfortunate for Ukraine. Yes.
Um, noise says Gia Taylor bronze g Pepsi
Pepsi P. What are you talking about?
Um, I have no idea what this is about.
Okay. 24 Bat says, "What is India's
ideology?
Is it socialist, secular or integral
humanism? NK has jina has socialism or
Chinese characteristics or confusionism?
Ideology guides sovereignty.
India's ideology I don't know what it is
really I don't know what it is I don't
know what integral humanism is I've not
studied it so I don't know what it is
okay uh but it definitely not is not
India's ideology
India is more of a social even today the
policies are very socialistic right I
think India's ideology is socialism and
secularism yeah like the constitution
says
secular sovereign republic or that sort
of thing
So uh if you see my Twitter account,
have you seen my Twitter account?
I'll show you in case some of you have
not seen. So India's ideology is
socialism, socialism and secularism
today.
So if you see my Twitter account,
if you see the biography,
it says that I'm neither secular nor
socialist.
So that's me just Yeah.
Uh but yeah, India's ideology is
socialism and secularism and that is
what it it it guides it determines the
long-term future of the nation, doesn't
it?
It does.
And what should our ideology actually
be? It should be dharma. That's what it
should be. But we are secular and
socialist.
That's sad and unfortunate because
neither secularism nor nor socialism is
Indian.
It's it's all foreign sad.
Anand but says Anandbut says my wife
says I can listen to you for 3 hours
with full attention but not her
but not her for 3 minutes
sending this message based on her
advice. Big fan. Thank you very much for
being being a big fan and thank you very
much for being able to listen to me for
three hours and u uh please give my
regards to your wife. Please give my
regards to her. Thank you so much and
thank you for making me laugh. Thank you
to your wife for making me laugh. Please
give her my regards.
Hyphen says, "Does India benefit more
from a stable West Asia or from a
weakened divided region where no single
power dominates? also means also miss
the science streams. Thanks. Okay,
science streams. Well, nobody watches
those science streams sadly. It's it's
like a 150 people watching at most.
So, um Okay. So, coming to the question,
does India benefit from a stable West
Asia or from a divided weakened region?
I think we benefit from a stable West
Asia. The West Asian nations most mostly
are friendly to us and we are big
customers of their main product which is
which is oil. So it's a win-win the
relationship for us as well as for them.
So we benefit from a stable West Asia.
We would like the region to be stable
and peaceful.
Okay. We don't want war in the region.
It messes things up for us. We want Iran
and the Gulf nations to all be friendly
with each other and peaceful. That's
what India benefits from. Yeah, a
weakened divided n region where no
single power dominates. If you have a
weakened divided region where no single
regional power dominates, what will
happen is that a a non-regional power
will dominate and that is that has been
the situation that's been the case for
decades.
The region is divided.
It is divided and the US dominates the
region.
The region is divided. How? You had Iran
versus Iraq in the past?
You have Israel that many nations oppose
in the region and then you have various
rivalries between the other nations as
well. So you keep the nation region
divided so that a foreign power can
actually dominate which is the US and
that's what you had for the longest
time. So what we would like to have is
no foreign power dominates the region.
There is a balance of power in the
region and peace and stability. That is
the ideal situation. Which means for
India what's ideal this war ends the
Americans withdraw and then there is
peace in the region. That is ideal for
us.
24 Bat says Sidan Sibil is a great exac
account for Indian news. Yes, he is. I
follow him. Yes, he's he's a great exac
account. He's like he knows, isn't he?
And uh you get the latest updates from
him like Yeah. So he's a great account
for news related to India. I agree with
you.
24 Bharat says Indians complaining about
missing Chinese officials is amusing. We
should be the we should be doing the
same idiots and purging corruption and
firing corrupt babos and opin and
officials.
So if Chinese officials are missing it
means they have been purged right and
they in China officials are typically
purged if they go against the nation or
if they are corrupt.
And it's not something amusing. It's not
something to make fun of China for.
You should respect China for doing that.
For cracking down on antinational
activities and cracking down on
corruption.
Yeah, I agree with you. Yes. And
ideally, ideally India should also do
that. India should crack down on
antinational activities and on
corruption just like China.
I completely agree with you but that's
not what happens. It doesn't happen in
India doesn't it? Sadly.
Okay. Dhir Kamat says Bobby Een is
taunting Dharmic people in the chat
trying to intimidate us insinuating that
Christianity is dominant and we should
be afraid. I Bobby Epen is a longtime
viewer of this channel
and even yesterday people were
complaining about him.
I find this very unfortunate that we
have this disruptive behavior in in this
channel.
So I'm going to have to take some action
about this sadly.
Okay.
Well, Djam, thank you so much for
bringing this to my notice. Thank you.
Villiant Prince says, "If Persians and
the Alina Greek clan were both among
other clans defeated by King Sudas,
would the Greeks also be considered Arya
like us and Persians?"
See, Arya from our perspective, from an
from an Indian dharmic perspective, the
word Arya means civilized.
area. Whether you're Arya or not is
determined by your conduct, by your
behavior, not by your blood, not by your
ethnicity.
Okay?
But today Indians imagine that Arian
means an ethnic thing and white people
are arians. That's what we have been
taught, right?
Arya means civilized. Your area or not
based on your behavior and your
comportment you conduct.
But if you want to give Arya racial the
word Arya or Aryan racial a racial
meaning like the Persians did later on
then who would be the the be the area?
It would be us and the Persians not the
Greeks
because the Greeks they went into Europe
and they intermarried as opposed to the
Europeans and they became whiter didn't
they? So look, if you look at whiteness,
okay, whiteness, then Indians, we are
brown. Persians are somewhat lighter
skinned than us today because the Turks
brought in lots of foreigners and and
settled them into Persia. But 2,000
years ago, the Persians were looked like
people from Western India, light brown
skin, etc. Uh, but the Greeks, they went
into Europe and they intermixed with the
Europeans. That's why they became whiter
than the Persians.
And uh
so that's why they would not be
considered to be fully pure blood aras
like Indians and Persians. But from the
proper meaning of the word area. Okay.
If you eat beef, you're no longer Arya.
If you no longer practice vic rituals,
you're no longer Arya.
And the Persians did practice Vic
related rituals like the yesnas and all.
So let's say the Persians were still
Arya but the Greeks no longer did that.
So you could not call them Arya.
So from our perspective blood doesn't
matter behavior matters. Okay. If you no
longer behave like a civilized person
you are a matcha.
Hershit Jane says if they take Chabahar
port will India have a problem. Moreover
you have just slight redness in your
left eye. Now it's my red left eye. Is
it
now? Oh, it's my left eye. There's a
slightly red. Okay, I'll not zoom in
again. But okay. Uh, all right. Just
slight redness. I think there's a red
light in this region. So, everything
appears red.
You see everything in this on this side
appears reddish because of this here and
so on. So, don't worry, I'm fine. The
redness is an illusion. It's all Maya.
So, now the question is if they take
Chabahar port, will India have a
problem? No. We have already walked out
of Chabahar. We have liquidated our our
um stake in Chabahar. We have paid
whatever we were supposed to pay to the
government of Iran and and we have we
are out of it. So we no longer operate
any part of Chabahar.
It will not cause any problems for us.
Iran says, "Should we Indians, not the
government citizens, be pro-Israel after
what happened to the girls school and
how much we citizens have suffered for
their war?" See, we Indians, forget
about the government of India. What
should our position as Indian citizens
be? What should our stance be as Indian
citizens? Our as Indian citizens, our
business is to be pro- India.
That's all. only be pro- India.
Don't don't be pro any other nation. Why
do we have to be pro some nation or the
other? We should only be pro- India. Be
very narrow-minded in this matter. Only
pro- India, nothing else. Don't be pro
any other government, any other nation.
Um, so that's how it should work.
And what happened to that girl school is
obviously horrific. It is unforgivable.
Whoever did that, it looks like the
Americans did that. Okay, not Israel.
Most likely it was the Americans who did
that. They most likely uh
fired a Tom to Tomahawk missile on that
school.
And it's not the first time the
Americans would have done done something
like that.
Um so my my my simple recommendation is
don't be pro any other nation only be
pro- India
when some nation cooperates with us it's
they are cooperating with us because it
serves their interests okay
international relations are all based on
self-interest.
So if you have good relations with the
nation, it's because it's only because
it is serving that nation's interests
and it's also serving our interests.
It's not because they love us or they
have something in common with us. Okay?
Please understand this. Be realistic.
I am not saying be anti-sumnation. I'm
not recommending any such thing. I'm
just saying be pro- India only. No,
don't be pro any other nation.
Craz says weak people give rise to tough
times. Tough times give rise to strong
people. Strong people create good times
and good good times create weak people.
The cycle continues. How to break the
cycle at an ideal situation? That is
strong people and good times. You can't
it's human nature that the cycle
continues. You can't break this. You
can't break this. Uh
this is in the context of uh dynastic
cycles and imperial cycles and that
inevitably happens
right inevitably happens. So if you want
a dynasty to last long or an empire to
last long you have to ensure that the
succession process always
gives the baiton to the best possible
candidate at all times. But that
obviously theoretically everybody
understands that but still it doesn't
work that way in in in real life. So you
can't break this cycle. This is simply
um it's caused by human nature and you
can't change that. Yeah. So can't break
the cycle.
Maharana says is hormones the multip
multipolar killsh shot for the dollar.
So, you've been a member for 49 months.
Good God. That's how many?
It's over four years. Thank you so much.
I have no idea. Thank you so much. I
really, really appreciate that. Okay.
The question is, is Hormos the
multipolar kill short for the dollar?
For the dollar, US dollar? It could
become that if this situation persists
and the Americans even after attempting
land invasions, ground invasions
whatever are unable to have to open the
the straight of Hormos if if they are
unable to open it at all then
and this situation persists let's say
hypothetically 6 months then yeah
the petro dollars could could start
crumbling
because if Iran becomes the dominant
power in the region they would force the
the the regional nations, the Gulf
nations to start selling the the you
know their oil, the product in in other
currencies, maybe the Chinese yuan or
something else. So this could be the
beginning of that process. It will all
depend on how things go in the next in
the next phase of the war.
Siddesh Pandar says Siddesh Pandar okay
Modi G mentioned seaweed in his latest
speech are we finally trying out seaweed
bofuel it could be a huge advantage
given our massive coastline okay I'm not
I'm not aware of this let me see what
Mr. Modi has said
um okay
Narendra Modi seaweed
what do they say?
Prime Minister Modi is actively
promoting seaweed cultivation India to
boost the blue economy enhance
fisherman's incomes strengthen the rural
economy. His government supports the
sector through the Pradhan mantra matya
sadaijana
with special emphasis on establishing
cultivation clusters and empowering
coastal communities. So seaweed
production could be a key
non-traditional income source.
Uh promotion of se
blah blah blah munchie bath fisher folk
strong foundation fisheries and seaweed.
I'm not sure what uh is to be done with
the seaweed.
Um
see what are the uses what are the uses
of seaweed? People consume seaweed in
some countries as a food. You can turn
seaweed into bofuel. You can can you use
it as a fertilizer? I suppose you can
transform it into fertilizer.
So
some of some seaweed species have
medicinal properties.
So I'm not sure what the what India
hopes to achieve through seaweed.
Um
okay let's see
how is seaweed used in India
raw material for industrial ficoids
aigar and all these things organic bio
fertilizers and agriculture
pharmaceutical and neutrautical products
um yeah so we are not really looking
into looking at making this turning this
into bofuel doesn't look like that. So
I'm not aware of what Mr. Modi has said.
I'm just trying to quickly take a look
at what the Google AI is saying. And it
doesn't look like there's any emphasis
on turning seaweed into bofuel.
And to turn seaweed into bio, you'd have
to extract massive quantities of
seaweed, which could devastate the
seaweed populations actually. So I think
better than that it makes sense to to
use the biomass which that is a waste
product from the 1.4 billion Indian
people that should be used to to produce
bofuuel that makes more sense in my
opinion and you would have to create a
whole infrastructure for that but it's
certainly possible.
Uh so yeah it doesn't look like we are
looking into
turning seaweed into bofuel doesn't
doesn't look like that.
Pratik Kumar Roy says, "I have seen some
people on the internet telling that
Pakistan is the next target of US and
Israel. So we should support them
against Iran.
Why would they attack Pakistan? I
wonder.
So some people are the theory that some
people are proposing is that once Israel
and the US are done with Iran, they will
attack Pakistan.
And that's why we should support the US
and Israel against Iran.
What
is the guarantee that once they done
done with Iran hypothetically they will
go against Pakistan? Pakistan is their
asset. Why will they destroy it? I don't
know who comes up with this theories but
I don't agree with this at all.
Yeah, I agree with the question. Why
would they why would they attack
Pakistan? I don't see any logical reason
why the US and Israel would attack
Pakistan today. Pakistan is their asset.
They will not attack it attack it. So I
I don't agree with this theory. I think
it's um it doesn't make sense.
Godz says news from the last few weeks
stating heavy casualty numbers for for
Russia and now UK is using its navy to
seize Russian tankers. It seems Russia
is stuck worse than Ukraine than worse
in Ukraine than the US in is in Iran.
Yeah, it looks like that from whatever
we are hearing in the news. So the
question is why is Russia not fighting
back? Russia has a massive
military.
It's not used its air force essentially
at all in the Ukraine war. Very, very
minimal air force involvement.
And I'm sure they have plenty of
missiles and they're producing missiles
in very large quantities and roads in
very large quantities. So why why isn't
Russia employing the same tactics and
methods and strategies the Americans are
employing in Iran?
Whatever options the Americans have on
the table in Iran, Russia also has the
same options on the table visav Ukraine.
They can destroy Ukrainian power plants.
They can destroy Ukraine Ukraine's um
water supply. They can destroy they can
do other things the Americans have done.
So why is Russia not doing that is the
question that I am unable to answer. Is
there some kind of secret understanding
with the US of some kind that once the
Americans are done with Iran, the
Russians will be given Ukraine? Is there
is there some such thing? Does Mr. Putin
still believe American promises?
I'm not sure what the deal is, but looks
like Russia is being hit hard right now
and it's not able to respond and it
looks like it's stuck really bad in in
Ukraine. Looks like that. So I would
agree with you. Yes.
Gorov contractor says your take on
Islamabad beat that happened today. I am
not aware of this. I'm not a news
surfer. I don't know what's happening in
real time. It doesn't matter what's
happening in real time. Long-term is
what matters. But let me see what is
this Islamabad meet.
Islamabad meeting.
What happened? Pakistan hosts talks with
Saudi Arabia, Turkey, Egypt or Iran war.
See, Pakistan doesn't matter in the Iran
war. Saudi Arabia doesn't matter. Turkey
doesn't matter. Egypt doesn't matter.
The nations that matter in the Iran war
are the US, Israel and Iran.
Okay. So what was the objective of this
uh of this thing of this conference or
whatever?
Um
let's see. Dawn is a Pakistani website.
Yeah. Ways for early and permanent end
to the Middle East war discussed at
quadrilateral moot says Dar.
Foreign ministers of Pakistan, Egypt,
Turkey and Saudi Arabia photographed
during a quadrilateral
uh huddle.
Okay.
Okay. So they are trying to uh they're
trying to find ways and means for an
early end and and permanent end to this
war.
Look, as long as the US wants to fight
and Israel wants to fight, what can
these nations do?
Okay, so I don't think it's very
consequential what's happening in in
Islamabad. Doesn't really make much of a
difference to the war. It's the US and
Israel that are calling the shots. And
it's Iran that's fighting back. These
nations can't do much about it. So
unless they can persuade the US and
Israel to end the war, there's nothing
much they can do by holding these
conferences and talks. Nothing much.
Push Suri has become a new member. Thank
you very much, sir. Push G and welcome
to the channel's membership. Thank you.
Neil Shaw says big fan. Thank you. The
Uttarakhan state government has
introduced the Ramayan and Gita into its
school curriculum to promote value-
based education thoughts. Well, as long
as these uh subjects are taught
properly,
that's good. I think it's good.
See the Gita, the Bhagat Gita gives you
incredible life lessons. The Ramayan is
is one of the core foundations of our
culture, right?
And the Mahabharat is a is I think it's
it's a little more
you know chanakin than the Ramayan.
The Mahabharat came later of course. So
I think Ramayan and Bhagat Gita of
course the Bhagat Gita is something that
is that is embedded in the Mahabharat,
isn't it? So uh I think my thoughts what
are my thoughts? I think this is a great
idea as long as the these concepts and
and these these these subjects are
taught properly. Yeah. Without any
distortions.
In that case, it's excellent. I'm very
pleased to hear this.
Amit Sharma says, "How strong is the
relationship between China and Iran? And
is China secretly supporting Iran?"
China is not secretly supporting Iran.
It's essentially openly supporting Iran.
In what sense? No. no direct involvement
of China in the war but China has given
Iran access to its uh BEu satellite
positioning system. Beu is the Chinese
version of GPS. The Russians have also
given Iran Glonas which is the Russian
version of GPS and the Chinese BEu seems
to be in some way superior to the
American GPS system. So that's one
thing. Second thing is that there are
Chinese spy satellites uh that are
giving Iran information about what's
happening on the ground in close to real
time. So that's another help that China
is offering to Iran. Now why is China
doing this?
Because China wants Iran to continue to
exist. Iran is an opponent of the US.
China, Russia, Iran are the three major
powers that still stand up to the US.
almost nobody else does. Right? So, and
China it it imports oil from Iran. Iran
is a major supplier of oil to China.
Between 50 to 15 to 20% of China's oil
comes from Iran. And if the Americans
win this war, then that will be shut off
to China or it will be available to
China only if the only
uh under American conditions.
So that's why China wants Iran to not be
defeated and that's why the Chinese are
supporting Iran and the Chinese have uh
a 25-y year strategic agreement deal
with the with the Iranians and the the
terms of the deal are uh not known.
They're secret. So this relationship is
pretty strong. Yeah.
Any plans for long content based on
books like UA? What's UA?
Oh, understanding America. Uh, right now
that is not on the cards, but that that
uh project is right now on ice, but it's
not it's not been cancelled. So, in the
future, it may I will resume it at the
right time. Uh, but right now, no other
plans because of the way things are
going right now in the world.
WBKT says, "Thad Tad
IRGC's
targeting precision is underrated." All
right, sir. Okay.
Uh,
Jimmy Lee says, "How was your childhood
growing up in a EU nation during the
Cold War?" I grew up I spent a few years
in Switzerland
in the city of Geneva mostly. Janev
Switzerland is not part of the EU as far
as I understand. Is it now a part of the
EU? It was not a part of the EU. There
was no EU back in the day. Uh, so my
childhood was nice. Switzerland is a
very pretty place. Yeah. Uh, my primary
language was French.
There was a time when I used to think in
French. So it was my primary language
for a while and it was nice. It was
nice.
Yeah.
Godliness says hypothetically if this US
Iran war turns into an energy disaster
causing famine in countries like
Bangladesh cres of people can line up on
our borders for refuge then what? Many
will illegally enter. Well, if crows of
people line up on our borders, they
should be kept out.
Our responsibility is towards our
citizens.
Okay? We are not responsible for the
citizens of other nations. That's not
how it works.
So if crows of people hypothetically
line up on our borders for refuge, they
have to be kept out.
They should not be allowed to illegally
enter.
The way things are right now, if this
happens tomorrow morning, many will like
you say illegally enter. Well, the
government needs to plan for these
uh contingencies.
Let's say in 6 months time there is an
issue like this then we should plan for
that right now and put the requisite
you know things in place to ensure that
if there are attempts for millions to to
enter India that none of them is able to
succeed.
So the government of India, the central
government needs to start making
preparations for such eventualities
right now itself and not a single
foreigner should be allowed to enter
India illegally. Legally is a different
matter. They should be welcomed if they
are entering legally. All legal
uh foreign foreigners all foreigners who
are entering India legally should be
welcomed but no illegal entry.
Okay, Neil Sha says, "You have also
mentioned that Hinduism might not
survive the next 100 years, but I feel
like it has more chances than others
considering even urban India was were
found to be only 3 or 4% less
religious."
Okay. Uh so
I I hope that you are right. You see u
nobody will be more pleased than me if
if our culture and our religion survives
may way more than next 100 years.
The way things are going right now it I
fear for the future of our culture our
civilization and our religion our
religions
I fear for the future. Uh
and why do I say this? It's because I
see people becoming more and more
dassinated.
And how many people in urban parts of
India actually practice their their
religion?
There are some cultures, some religions
in which you're supposed to pray five
times a day. There are some religions in
which you're supposed to every month pay
a 10% tithe to the local authorities and
you're supposed to have mass once a week
or whatever it is Sundays and these
people they they follow this
religiously.
But the people who practice our
religions, nonforeign religions, Indian
culture, how many of us in in urban
cities, urban centers even practice our
religion? So because of various issues
like this, I am a little, you know,
worried
about the survival of our culture and
civilization. But uh but I hope you are
entirely 100% correct and I hope that
I'm entirely wrong. I hope so. So I hope
that you are right. Let us be
optimistic.
Yawwanchi says, "Iran may target
undersea cables. Could this trigger
Starlink's rise in our region? Trump
trying to warp this war quick. Will
Israel let him Trump trying to wrap this
war up quickly? Will Israel let him do
that?" I if Israel wants to keep on
fighting, I don't think they will allow
Trump to walk out of the war and Trump
won't be able to, I suppose. Now if the
Iranians target undersea cables uh that
will cause disruptions in India
definitely and it will cause longer
latency times and all that in India is
going to degrade internet services in
India for sure. In some parts of India
it may even be disrupted for some time.
So could this trigger Starink's rise in
the region? That's a very good question.
I hope not. So if that sort of thing
happens the Americans will immediately
offer Starling to India. Let's go ahead.
Let's operationalize Starlink. Please
give us the per permissions.
I hope the government of India says no
to that if this happens
because Starlink is is is a threat to
India. Like I've explained many times.
It means now if we if we allow Starlink
to operate in India
then we are no longer in control of who
of way of of the internet in the
country. We can't switch it off if
required. And Starlink has been used in
regime change operations multiple times.
Elon Musk once tweeted that if if that
we will provide Starling in a in a
certain country and if the government is
a problem they can raise they can shake
their fist at the sky but nothing will
change.
We can't have starling in India.
Absolutely not. So I hope the government
says no to any such proposals if this
sort of situation happens.
Bhaskar Gupta says play
Roth.
Okay, you want to reverse this because
it's not allowed normally. Ask
Aru
A R A H Rahul. Ask Rahul to connect me
via mail on
V I S H O D I
um okay listen I don't have
I'm not able to copy paste this these
words from here so I won't be able to do
it but uh I suppose Aul can take a
screenshot and and reverse it all right
Okay.
Illuminate by Tarun. Thank you very
much, Tarun. Thank you.
24 Bat says, "Major General Bakshi
G Major General Dr. GD Bakshi. He's so
cool. True nationalist. He is quite the
man, isn't he? I'm a big fan of Dr.
Major General Dr. GD Bakshi G. He's also
a scholar. Do you know he's written a
book on the Sarasati civilization,
right?
Great man. Absolutely. And and and and
great fun to listen to, isn't he?
And I've once shared a stage with him.
Uh
should I Okay, give me a second. There's
this video on on my channel that I can
show you on in which he's also there on
on on the stage.
Give me a second. Let's let's let's
let's do this.
Okay. So, this is my channel. Let's go
to videos.
Okay. We'll search for this
invasion. Invasion.
Let's see. Do you find this?
Yeah, this one. It's an overview of the
Arian invasion migration myth. And if
you see the thumbnail, Dr. Giddy Bakshi
is standing next to me and this was a
book release function of of his book on
the Sarasota civilization. So yes,
awesome gentleman isn't he
that says
okay
I see what you did there that says who
will succeed Soros? Will he be a threat
for India? I can't say who will succeed
Soros. Maybe his son will succeed Soros.
His son is married to this is Pakistani
American person right Huma Abedin who
was uh um working for uh Madame Hillary
Clinton so could be his son I suppose
and these people are all threats for
India absolutely
okay hyphen says everyone is choosing
sides India is choosing discounts as it
should be as it should be right India
should not take any sides India should
not choose sides. India should choose
discounts. So India is doing the right
thing and I approve of it. Yes sir.
Uh Pratip Kumar Roy says some
Indian-American guy on the internet said
the suban civilization was the oldest.
Also ancient Indians came from Iraq and
Syria that region.
Okay, let them say it. How do we care?
We should not get upset about this.
Okay, this is the prevailing dogma. It's
the prevailing dogma in academia. And
that's what's taught to everybody. See,
most people don't want to think. I
personally used to be a complete
believer in the RN invasion theory. And
I used to get annoyed when people used
to say that, you know, the iron invasion
theory is fake. I used to get annoyed
because I spent a lot of time not
thinking about this. Then one day I
thought, okay, I decided, let me look
into this myself.
Let me look into the actual evidence,
not the textbooks, not the history
books. let me look at the actual
evidence, the archaeological evidence,
the genetic evidence and so on so forth.
Let me look at the actual pieces of
evidence. So I went through research
papers. I went through a lot of stuff.
And then eventually I realized what the
hell I was completely wrong to to
believe in the iron invasion theory. And
that's when I wrote that article uh the
Arian invasion myth. And in case you
want to read that article, let me plug
it right here. Okay. So let's see. Arian
invasion myth. Chavda
you can read it on medium you can read
it on um
India facts you can read it on uh the
original yeah the original article was
on India facts here it is okay this is
the original article it was written in
May 2017 that's 9 years ago and this
article is still the gold standard this
is where the entire matter started
because I was the first person to put
all the pieces of information from so
many different fields together.
Okay, this is the OG article 2017.
Before this article, you will not find
any article on the internet which
debunks this. Today, everybody's an
expert. Everybody says it's it's a it's
it's a myth and all, but this is the
article they are all referring to
without they will not they will not
admit it, but this is the article
everybody has been referring to. So,
check it out if you if you so wish.
Hyphen says, "Is this a war or just a
global price or oil price update?" Well,
it's it's a war, but it's also
messing up the global oil prices for
sure. Um, so it's a war that is having
the effect of updating the glo global
oil prices and the global oil prices are
being are being pushed upwards
deliberately,
especially by Ukraine targeting the
Russian oil export facilities, right?
the three ports they've been targeting
over the past three four days.
So yeah, it's going to cause a
tremendous amount of pain it looks like
on or ordinary people around the world
which is sad.
Empty box says how to deal with social
anxiety. Any tips? Social anxiety. What
is social anxiety? I suppose it is the
it is anxiety you feel while having
social interactions?
Uh I think I suppose you have to find
the root cause of your social anxiety.
What is it that makes you anxious? Why
do you become anxious while having
social interactions?
That is what you have to discover for
yourself.
And then you have to I think address
that or or go beyond or transcend that
whatever it is whatever the root cause
is. So some people are introverts and
they're not comfortable you know
interacting socially that is one cause u
some people are shy I think shy and
being introverted is it similar I I
don't know so introversion can make it
you know uncomfortable for people to
have social interactions
uh what else maybe you imagine you are
not very good-looking
which is why you imagine that people are
judging you and that's why you feel
anxiety I don't know there are lots of
potential causes for social anxiety. So
you have to find you to discover the
root cause for you. Why is it you know
why does why do you have social anxiety?
Why does social interaction cause
anxiety for you? You to find it out for
yourself and then find the solution for
that and the simplest way to do this is
to perhaps speak to a professional I
suppose of some kind. I'm not sure what
are the professionals who deal with
social anxiety but yeah main thing is
introspect. Spend some time thinking
about why you become anxious and once
you discover the root cause find the way
to solve it. All right. All the best.
Empty box.
Okay. Illuminatun says my name is Rayan.
All right. Uh can we call this war World
World War II? How does it impact India?
It's not World War II yet. It's still a
regional war. uh because there is apart
from the US there's no other uh non-
regional play player in this war right
now it's Israel versus Iran and the Gulf
nations are collateral damage and the US
is the external actor in here beyond
these nations nobody else is involved so
right now it's not world war II but if
let's say European nations get involved
if China gets involved if Russia gets
involved more directly then it could
then you could call if Pakistan gets
involved even if Pakistan is involved
it's still a local regional war but if
China Russia and European nations get
involved, that's when you can start
calling it World War II. How does it
impact India? Oil prices rising, gas
shortages potentially. This is this is
how it impacts India.
Okay. Uh humanity survive says, "Do you
know about the 20 2020 rule for screen
usage?" I am not aware of it. Let me
see.
20-20
rule for screen usage.
What is that?
Okay. To uh American Optometric
Association says to alleviate digital
ice strain. Where is it?
To help alleviate digital ice train,
follow the 2020 2020 rule. Take a 20
second break to view something 20 ft
away every 20 minutes. Oh, very
interesting. Take a 20 second break.
Let's zoom in. Let's bigify this
ambigen.
Let's embigen it even more. Even more.
Okay. To help alleviate digital eye
strain, follow the 20 2020 rule. And
what's the 20 2020 rule? Take a 20
second break to view to view something
20 ft away every 20 minutes.
Interesting. Sounds like a great um you
know way of uh sounds like a great thing
to do. Well, I wasn't aware of this.
Sounds logical. Makes sense. Every 20
minutes, 20 ft away, 20 seconds. Good. I
shall practice this because I spend a
lot of time staring at screens. I do.
Yes. Thank you so much. Humanity
survives. Thank you so much. I really
appreciate this and I thank you on
behalf of all my viewers because it'll
help everybody. Thank you.
Hyphen says, "No question, just don't
want the stream to end."
I really appreciate that. I'm I'm I'm so
glad I'm thankful that you enjoy my
these live streams and I thank you for
being a viewer and everybody else as
well. Thank you so much.
Uh Raman Gil says, "Energy lockdowns
coming. Time to return to the
motherland."
Okay, you you are paying in Canadian
dollars. I suppose you must be I suspect
you must be in Canada in that case.
Energy lockdowns coming. I hope they
don't come. And if you're in Canada, you
won't have energy lockdowns because
Canada is a big major producer of of
oil. At least oil. Let me see how much
how much No, that's not the right
question.
What is Canada's rank among the oil
producing nations? That's a good
question. That's a better question to
ask.
Canada is the world's fourth largest oil
producer and fourth largest exporter. So
if you are in Canada then you will have
no issues whatsoever. They will have no
energy lockdowns.
Canada is the world's fourth largest oil
producer.
But if you are not in Canada
um and if you are in a nation that could
have energy lockdowns
well if you return to the motherland
India what if there are s there's a
similar situation in India in India as
well. I don't know. I think right now
just wait it out. returning to the
motherland may not make things much
better for you. You may have a similar
situation in the motherland as well. So
yeah, my my suggestion is please make
please do your own due diligence,
consult your local experts as to how
things may turn out to be and uh
consider all the pros and cons, all the
risk factors and make your decision
after being thoroughly informed and
after doing your research thoroughly.
All right. All the best.
Kedict member Bach
says, "What's your opinion on Palm Beach
Pete? Is he him?"
Okay, I somehow know what you're talking
about.
I I I somehow know what you're talking
about. How is that? Is he him?
I I'm a little skeptical. I'm a little
skeptical that he is Jeffrey Epstein.
Yeah, in case.
Let's see. Jeffrey Epstein spotted
somewhere right on Palm Beach.
Palm Beach Pete.
So, yeah, Jeffrey Epstein's
doppelganger. Let's go to images.
I I don't think it's him. I don't think
it's him.
It's definitely someone who looks quite
similar, but it's most likely a
different person.
Most likely a different person.
Yeah, I I I think it's a different
person, but who knows? I may be wrong.
Who knows?
Okay.
IPKS says sir Bobby banita
he tried.
What happened? He tried what?
He tried.
I look I have been getting these
complaints for a very long time. Uh we
want a peaceful experience. So it is
what it is.
Hershi Jin says I don't think ground
troops will find fight anywhere. It's
just a display for the world
and suddenly we will see a ceasefire and
Trump declaring no need for ground
invasion
even though the US was ready to fight.
So you don't think there's going to be a
ground invasion? It's possible it's it's
all a bluff. It's possible it's a bluff
by Trump, right? See, like Sunzu said,
you have to mislead and misdirect your
enemies.
So you never know maybe they they the
real objective is something else
entirely.
So one hopes there'll be a ceasefire
soon. I hope so. Yeah I hope so. But we
also have to consider the military
buildup uh seriously. They are bringing
in large numbers of troops now. So we
have to and Iran will have to take it
very seriously of course.
Okay. uh only facts and data says
multipolar world first step to type one
civilization.
So you're talking about uh the Kardashev
scale here and on the Kardashev scale a
type of civilization is a civilization
that that is able to control and harness
all the energy
and resources on its home planet.
A multipolar world is not the first step
in that direction.
For a kardashev type one civilization,
you need a uniolar world with a one
world one world government. Only then
it'll it'll
most likely that's the only condition in
which it can happen. Okay. Goro TV says,
"Trump's nature is understandable, but
why is Sentcom even considering a ground
invasion when US's most potent and
divisi decisive force, the air power,
has already failed to neutralize Iran?"
Well, they have their own
considerations. They have their own
calculations. They have their own
analysis,
their own logic.
Um
so we know that air power has failed to
neutralize Iran and
the objective is to win somehow right?
Trump wants to win. So if air power is
not working, Trump will say let's try
something else.
We can't use naval power because we
can't cross the street of Hormos. So now
let's try a ground invasion. I suppose I
don't know what the rational is. I think
a ground invasion is is is likely to be
suicidal.
knowing everything we know about Iran's
preparations and Iran's geography and
terrain,
right?
So, uh I think it's it's it's not the
right thing to do. I think it's very
dangerous for the US. So, I don't know
if it's actually going to happen, right?
But looks like it's being considered
very seriously. For example,
for example,
we have this message that has gone out.
We have this message that has gone out.
Um, and I'll not read it all over again,
but it looks like the Americans are
preparing are preparing the soldiers
mentally, the Marines mentally. Yeah.
So uh it's still all hypotheticals right
now but maybe there are calculations
that said that you know maybe the US has
a chance to to grab some territory and
hold on to it. We'll see.
Amirkar says out of topic but finding
deep breathing and sudash sudashan kria
heal overthinking. So in your experience
deep breathing and sudashan kria they
heal overthinking. Well, great. Great.
uh sudri kria is uh the technique that
is used by uh
by the disciples of uh shria ravishankar
gji right and it is a technique that he
has I think invented or or discovered
shishi ravishankar gj um and I think it
has something to do with breath work
right breathing deep breathing in uh
control breathing okay so I'm I'm glad
it's it's working for you Good
Pratip Kumar Roy says, "Why do men from
good families even marry nowadays? It's
dangerous, demeaning and a lossmaking
venture in this feminist anti-Hindu
India. Sometimes I feel like the Muslims
are right. They are not cowards."
Well, I you know, you're supposed to
marry, you're supposed to continue your
lineage, right? You're supposed to one
of the reasons for existing is that you
exist because your forefathers
procreated and it is a duty that you
have to procreate to continue uh your
lineage, your civilization, all of that.
So that's why I think I I I personally
think that everybody should marry but
you have to marry carefully. You have to
be very careful about who you marry
and as individuals you may not be able
to make the right choices which is why
you need to take the help of family you
know and that's called arranged
marriage. I think today as long as
families are involved, elders in are
involved, arranged marriages are way
less likely to be dangerous to you than
love so-called love marriages. And even
then, it's not guaranteed that it'll be
fine because these days girls, I don't
know what they are being taught, but
they feel like it's okay to I don't
know, do whatever happens these days.
And uh yeah, the laws and everything is
is it's all loaded against man men,
right?
Yeah, but look what happens if you stop
marrying or or or the option is you you
don't marry but have kids nonetheless.
Well, then we are going in the same
direction as the west, broken societies,
broken families. So the solution to all
of this is to clean up the act to to fix
our legal system to fix the laws
and the laws should be gender neutral,
not biased in in favor of a certain
gender. The law should not be biased in
favor of women or men or men. They
should be completely genderneutral. They
should be completely impartial. That's
what needs to happen. But yes, I
understand why young men feel this way.
I do understand why they feel this way.
And it's it's terrible.
Um,
Vision says, "You spent a you spent a
considerable amount of your childhood
abroad. How did you prevent yourself
from becoming a version of Aub or Panu?
Um,
Aayub or Panu? I don't know who Aub is.
I may perhaps know who Aub is. I'm not
sure and I will not the full name here.
And Singh Pano.
How did I prevent myself from becoming
like that? Look, I was completely
westernized when I was abroad.
And honestly when I came back to India I
wasn't very pleased about coming back to
India. Okay as a child as a child but
then you grow then you learn then you
become more mature.
So I don't know how it happened I was
very westernized
my primary language was French
but the way my life went it brought me
to where I am today. Okay. I think it
was a good thing that happened to me
that I spent certain amount of of time
certain number of years abroad because I
got to see the world at the time as a
child and again as an adult I did travel
again. So if you travel to various parts
of the world you know you understand the
world better that's why I I highly
recommend to everybody to travel as far
as as much as possible depending on how
much resources you have. if you have the
resources do travel so that you see the
world and see see the way people live in
other parts of the world.
Uh but somehow or the other um I ended
up where I am today. I don't yeah I
haven't exactly analyzed in depth how I
did not become this or that but I'm glad
I I I ended up where I am today.
Apar says why can't India switch to
biogas and save on forex rather than LPG
because we have biogas plants like like
a cottage industry in some scattered
parts of India it's not a full-fledged
thing all across India right to have bio
gas plants everywhere in India you will
have to set up the infrastructure for
that which will cost a lot of money and
politicians don't like spending money on
things they like spending money on
freebies
setting up a in a pan India bio gas
infrastructure
it's going to be very expensive but it's
going to be a tremendously beneficial
long-term investment
right India will become completely
self-sufficient at least in terms of
cooking gas and even India may even have
a surplus that it could potentially sell
to the countries because we've got 1.4 4
billion people and all the waste that is
generated
okay not just as a consequence of our
digestion but also cooking and all that
tremendous amount of biomass is
generated so India should switch to that
but that's a process that will take
about 2 to 5 years to set up the
infrastructure everywhere some states
may not cooperate and all that that's
always the problem in India federalism
there are political issues there are
logistical issues and so much money to
spend instead of giving freebies for
votes. Who will do that? So there are
these issues. I hope somebody has the
visionary leadership to do this. I hope
so.
Polomial says, "Any suggestions for
interesting topics that I need to be
researched that need to be researched
just like you did for iron invasion
theory? Not necessarily just in history
but other domains." Oh, I have a bunch
of topics in physics that need to be
researched. Very big open questions,
open problems in physics. Um,
what's dark matter? What's dark energy?
Do we have the answers? We don't. What's
gravity? We don't know the what what
gravity is.
I mean, we know what Newton said about
gravity. That's not entirely correct. We
know what Einstein said about gravity.
General relativity. The best theory we
have. Even that has problems.
And then so what is gravity? What is
dark matter? What is dark energy? We
don't know the we don't know the
answers. Big open problems. What is
time?
What's time?
Then outside of physics, what's
consciousness?
Very very interesting topics we don't we
don't have the answers to and I'm sure
there's so much more. So if you ask me
this question, the first things that
come to my to my mind is the the open
questions in physics. Uh apart from
that, there are many other topics in
history and other things I'm I'm sure
that are very interesting. Uh but I
can't think of those right now. What
comes to me off the top of my head is
always physics.
Okay.
Aditya Vashinkar says USA calls India
key. Trump Musk Modi talk thoughts. I
don't care. I don't care what they say.
I only care about their actions. Trump
said something nice about India. It
doesn't mean we should start celebrating
that everything is good in the world.
Okay. So Trump Musk Modi had a talk. It
it means most likely that there was
would have talked about Starlink
possibly.
Maybe the Americans want a the Indians
to operationalize Starlink within India
to give Starlink permission to start
beaming its signal into India. I don't
know. That's a possibility. Why else
would Elon Musk be involved? I don't
think they would talk about Twitter or
X, right? I don't think they'll talk
about Grock, Tesla, not really. Most
likely it would be about Starlink
and about the Americans calling India a
key nation. I don't care. I don't need
your praise.
So uh understand that the India US
relationship is very complicated.
It is um it's not
u we don't have shared interests.
We have some shared interest little bit
little bit and we don't have shared
values
and the US is not behaving like a
friendly nation towards India. Please
understand that. So it's complicated.
the the relationship is complicated and
difficult.
Shirang Shetty says, "Your view, your
take on Professor Jang's predictions. I
am not aware of his predictions. I don't
watch the guy. I'm sure he's very
interesting. I'm sure he's brilliant.
I've seen a couple of his clips and he
does sound like he knows what he's
talking about, but I haven't seen his
long videos and I have no idea what
predictions he's made." I think one
prediction he made is that that Iran
will win this war against the US.
So that is something that
I
tend to agree with at this point in time
that Iran won't be defeated
and at the end of the war whenever it
happens it's going to be the US that
ends up on the non-winning side at least
if not the defeated side. So I would
agree with that. I don't know about he
has something some theory of pax judika
or something I hear. I am not aware of
what the details of this theory are but
I don't know. So uh since I have not
watched any of his long videos, I can't
really say much about the predictions
apart from the Iran winning this war
thing.
Pratep Kumar Royce says, "I have seen
most Hindu men in my previous
generations to be mostly cowards without
an iota of self-respect because of
Bollywood maybe unlike people from other
religions. I hope things are changing
nowadays." Okay, I not sure why you why
you feel that way. If you talk about
previous generations, we have
Chhatraatishwaji Baharaj, we have Mahana
Mahana Pratab Prattab, we have so many
Hindu men who fought for our culture,
our civilization and gave up their lives
for us.
But if you're talking about personal
experience of people you have seen with
your own eyes, well maybe it's the case.
I don't know about that. Uh overall we
we are still a society that is
recovering from roughly 1,000 years of
foreign occupation in various parts of
India. I'm not saying the whole of the
subcontinent was under foreign
occupation for thousand years. It was
progressively expanding uh foreign
occupation
and we are suffering from the
consequences of that. Even now we
haven't decolonized at all. We are a
nation today. India is a nation state.
We are a nation with PTSD and amnesia
together. What is PTSD?
PTSD is post-traumatic stress disorder.
Our society has taken tremendous trauma.
It has suffered tremendous trauma.
So when you suffer
trauma there is post-traumatic stress
disorder PTSD
where you have symptoms that you can't
explain but which are which are caused
by the trauma that you experienced in
the past. So India has PTSD but it but
India also has amnesia which means it
can't remember what happened to it. Why
can't we remember what happened to us?
Because our education system doesn't
teach us that.
So we don't know what happened to us and
we have these symptoms of post-traumatic
stress disorder.
That's why India is a deeply confused,
deeply troubled nation
and that's why you have these problems
in people in in in India where some
people maybe like you say exhibit
symptoms of cowardice or whatever.
So what needs to happen is we have to
first of all heal the amnesia by
teaching our people the true history of
what happened in the past 1,000 years
and removing all the lies and
distortions
about our culture, our civilization, our
religion, our history, all of that.
That's the first thing first step that
needs to be taken. How do you do that?
By reforming the education system.
That's why I keep saying the education
system is the key to everything.
And then once we understand what
happened, we can start dealing with the
stress and the PTSD and then we can
start actually addressing the PTSD. So
that's what needs to happen. But the
government of India doesn't doesn't want
to make any of these changes.
Polomial says would you bet on acquiring
deep knowledge without would you bet on
acquiring deep knowledge about mining
and refining rare earths and energy
cause India will have to do that soon
maybe in 20 years. India needs to have
done that yesterday. Actually, India has
the world's largest reserves of rare
earth minerals of rare earth elements.
But we don't mine and refine any of
that. India needs to start doing this at
the earliest, not in the next 20 years,
the next 5 to 10 years maximum.
And when it comes to energy, yes, we
need to discover our own sources of
energy. maybe in the andmans wherever if
we discover large res reserves in the
andmans we're going to have to
significantly bulk up our navy to to
defend what is ours. So these things
need to happen urgently urgently
urgently we are running out of time the
world is changing very rapidly and now
it's very open openly the case that
might is right so we need this
says Chinese GPS versus Indian Navic GPS
which is better the Indian Navic GPS is
dead it is not functional anymore
and the Indian Navic system when it was
functional was was confined only to the
subcontinent and slightly beyond the
subcontinent. It is not a global system.
The Indian Navic, the Chinese BU is a
global system. They have a global
constellation of geostationary
satellites. The Indian Navic GPS system
was a local system. Small ambitions for
India and now it's no longer functional.
So the Chinese system is way way way
better. That's a sad truth.
Ja Gada says used machine learning media
pi and open CV
are I 70% more blink 10% more red than
left eye
okay you used machine learning media pie
and open CV and the result is that my
right eye is blinking 70% more do eyes
blink independently of each other and
10% more red than the left eye. So my
right eye is 10% more red than my left
eye. 20% more fatigue compared to the
last four streams. You can Google those
models. See a doctor. All right. Thank
you so much. Thank you so much for this
diagnosis
and I shall Google those models and if
required I shall see a doctor. Thank
you. Thank you. I really appreciate the
concern. Thank you.
Pratipar Royce says difference between
dark energy and dark matter.
Okay, we kind of know what dark matter
could be. Dark matter is some
it's either some kind of particle or
maybe a class of particles. What kind of
particle or particles? Particles that
interact only gravitationally but not
through the electromagnetic or weak
interaction. Some dark matter models say
that particles could have the weak
interaction. But from my perspective,
pure dark matter, cold dark matter is uh
a particle or a class of particles that
interacts only gravitationally.
So if a particle does not interact
through the electromagnetic interaction,
it means it's invisible
because light, color, all of this is
electromagnetism in action. Photons
are the are the um you know
the mediator particles of the
electromagnetic interaction.
Um so dark matter
if you if you look at the universe out
there you see all the light you know all
the all the stars galaxies nebulas all
of that that all of that luminous
material matter it makes up about 4% of
the mass energy of the universe only 4%.
96% of the universe is unknown to us.
It's dark.
Now about 24 25% of that unknown
matter or energy and energy is dark
matter. And we know that we know this
because we can see this from the
rotation curves of galaxies and so on.
All most galaxies have big dark matter
hallows that we can't see but we can
sense them through gravitational
interactions. So that is dark matter.
That is some kind of unknown particle or
class of particles. Unknown particles.
Dark energy is even more mysterious. We
don't even know what it is. Is it a
fluid? Is it a substance? Is it a new
force? We don't know. But it accounts
for about 70% of the mass energy of the
universe. And it seems to be a fluid or
a substance or a force that is causing
the universe to expand in an
accelerating manner. Okay. So dark
energy could be a force or a fluid or a
substance of some kind. Very mysterious.
But dark matter is most likely some
class of particle or particles. Okay.
Hyphen says the only stream that feels
like our stream, not just the creator
stream. Thank you for all this free
knowledge, sir. Years to come. Thank you
so much. Thank you so much. I'm really
glad you like it. It's all it's yours
because it's driven by you, right? You
ask the questions, I answer them as as
best I can as as best I can. Sometimes I
can't but I try my best. So it's an
interaction between us, right? So it's
as much yours as as it is mine if not
more yours because you set the agenda. I
don't set the agenda, right? You ask the
questions and that's what drives the
streams. So it's all yours actually and
you're very welcome. Thank you so much.
Karan Ra says your take on broker
Pakistan. Won't it get get them
relevance? Broker Pakistan.
Pakistan is a broker is it? Did somebody
say something about broker?
Um what's my take on Pakistan? Uh
Pakistan is an artificial temporary
nation that is whose whose days are
numbered. Sooner or later it would break
up. That's how I see Pakistan. Uh that's
my take on them. I think Dr. J. Shankar
called them broker or something dal or
something. I don't care about that.
Words words. I don't it doesn't matter
to me.
Uh, Ajinkawa says, "What could be the
military applications of quantum
mechanics?" Well, let me give you one
military application of quantum
mechanics.
Quantum physics, the nuclear bomb. It's
all quantum physics. It's all quantum
mechanics, right?
So, that's one military application of
quantum mechanics.
Um, all technologies that we use today
are quantum mechanical in nature. See,
we are interacting right now. I'm
sitting here in this fantastic room. You
are sitting wherever you are. And
there's so many viewers who are watching
this live and so many who will watch it
later.
How are we communicating? How is this
live uh live stream possible? This live
telecast possible because of quantum
technologies. I'm using a computer of
some kind to transmit this. The computer
it's microchips. They will not function
without quantum without the applications
of quantum mechanics. semiconductors,
transistors, it's all quantum mechanical
in nature, right? I'm using camera
to do this. The camera, it's sensors,
all of that there, they're also quantum
mechanical in nature. So everything, all
technologies that we use today are
quantum mechan are on the are based on
the applications of quantum mechanics
and these technologies are used in war
as well, military applications,
all of them. So Apar Apar thank you very
much indeed. Thank thank you.
Uh yes Pash says I listen to you when I
drive HGV
driver Great Britain of today. Thank
you. You are very welcome indeed. You're
very welcome. Okay. What's an HGV? HGV.
Let me just quickly see what is an HGV.
Um,
HG. HG is Mercury, but there's a V here.
What's HGV? Oh, a heavy goods vehicle.
Okay.
Okay. You are driving a heavy goods
vehicle in the UK. Okay. Okay. Got it.
Got it. Got it. Well, thank you so much
for listening to me. It's a privilege
that I have you and other people
listening to listening to me and I'm
glad that I am able to provide some
value. So thank you very much and you
are very welcome. Thank you.
Rajat says once I intellectually started
to realize the difference between pure
consciousness and reflected
consciousness
on mind it changed me completely. So the
difference between pure consciousness
and reflected consciousness are we
talking about ada vidanta here?
Yeah. non-duality
the atman and the brahman is that what
you're talking about
yeah so that's a that's of course when
we discuss consciousness we are not
talking about physics because physics
can't define consciousness so we're
talking about philosophy spirituality
religion all of that so yes yes atman
and brahman
I I think that's what you're talking
about okay
jooshi says apparently Indian defense
minister set up a meeting dual secret
meeting and speculations about something
to happen.
We shall see. We shall see. All right.
Uh okay. Looks like something could be
happening if in case this is indeed the
what's happened the world secret
meeting. So if it's a secret meeting,
how how do we know about this?
But anyway, looks like look, this is a
sensitive time in international affairs
in geopolitics and uh our interests are
also at stake when it comes to this
ongoing war and it's not like we have
any shortage of enemies. So maybe
something is going on. We'll we'll keep
an eye on that. Okay. Apar says should
we also include shasta principles in
India for civics since reading
interesting things after reading the
land of seven rivers by Sanjepal.
Um
the arasha shastra is uh a treaties on
economics and state craft and and
international relations.
Okay. It's not about civic sense. It's
not about civics. It's about governance.
So it's a manual for kings and emperors
and for rulers.
Okay. And it still is very relevant.
Uh it's it's definitely an interesting
book to read, but it's not an easy read.
It's it's not easy to read. You have to
spend mental effort reading the book. So
yeah, I would certainly recommend
everybody reads that. Yeah. But it's not
something that will make will give
people civic sense. It's it's not for
that.
Pratip Kumar says, "Your views about the
land sealing act. None of my friends
have ancestry land except me. That two a
few acres all come from good good
families. Land Sealing Act. I'm not
aware of this. Let me see.
Land Sealing Act India.
Whoa.
Land Seeing Act. Okay. The land sealing
act in India limits the maximum land
holding any individual family can own
with surplus land acquired by the
government for redistribution to
landless farmers to reduce rural
inequality.
Under 1972 national guidelines, the
limit typically ranges from 10 to 10 to
18 acres for premium irrigated land to
27 to 54 acres for dry land.
This is this sounds like very
socialistic. This sounds very
This sounds like something a communist
or socialist government would would
impose.
The ceiling is generally applied to a
family of five, husband, wife and minor
children rather than an individual. Land
exceeding the set set limit is deemed
surplus and the government acquires this
land and then what do they do with it?
They make a royal mess of it. I suppose
um I think the motivation is good
but
the execution implementation may not not
be the best.
10 to 18 acres at most.
What? What do you What's an acre? Let me
just quickly find out what an acre is.
Acres to square meters.
Or acres.
Acres to square meters. So 1 acre is 20
by 20. Okay. 20 by 20 square m. An acre
is well that's pretty small then, right?
20 m by 20 m. 2020. two.
No, no, no. It's not 20 by 20. That That
would be 400.
Okay. What is the square root of 408 46?
What's the square root of 40 46?
63. It's 63 m on one side.
Okay. So, yeah. So, that's not a lot of
land. I think they can increase the
ceiling at least.
Okay. So, I don't have any initial
thoughts about this. I haven't I don't
know about this act and I haven't ever
thought about it. But my first initial
reaction is that it sounds something
like a something that a socialist or
communist government would do.
Yeah,
that's what it sound like. I have to
think I I will have to look it up in
detail and study a little more before I
I say anything about it.
Yeah, that's that's my first initial
reaction about this.
Okay. HC says, "If ground invasion by
the US, do I leave the UAE?"
Uh, it's it's see
I am probably not the right person to
give you advice about this, okay?
Because I don't live in the UAE. I I
don't have any any skin in the game. I
don't have any skin in the game.
UAE obviously is a wonderful, very nice
place. No question about that. So if
there's a ground invasion by the US,
what could happen?
Iran will fight the ground invasion. But
if if if the US is using the UAE and its
let's say air bases or whatever as as
staging grounds for the invasion, then
Iran will most likely hit out at the UAE
in that in in that case only.
Um
so I don't know
if the US doesn't use UAE territory for
staging the invasion then UAE may not be
hit will not be hit by Iran. See Iran
has been very very u
logical
and uh
it's been very logical in in its actions
and it's been retaliatory in its
actions. It's not preempted anything
this far. So it's been a very rational
actor though so so far it won't
unnecessarily
you know try to strike at the UAE.
So as long as the US doesn't use the UAE
as a staging area for the invasion I
don't think Iran will hit the UAE.
But if the US does use UAE's territory
then you can expect uh Iran to target
the UAE. So it depends on many factors.
I can't really tell you whether we
should leave the UAE or not.
Overall, the government of the UEE has
done a great job of sending those
alerts by by text message.
Yeah, I hope things things are good for
the UAE. But uh I I I am not the right
guy to answer this question. I'm not
because it depends on so many different
factors, right?
So yeah,
I think you will have to make your own
decisions based on your superior
understanding of the situation because
you are right there.
Uh but if this war continues for a long
time, I think it makes sense for
everybody to at least temporarily
at least temporarily leave the leave
this region. Okay. So let's say this war
hypothetically lasts 6 months or one
year. Hypothetically, I hope it ends
tomorrow, but hypothetically. So, it's a
possibility, isn't it?
So, I think it makes sense for people
who have the means to move move out that
they move out at least temporarily until
things settle down. That's what I would
do if I was there. I would leave the
place temporarily, then return once
things are normal. That's what I would
do. But I am not there. I'm just
speaking in hypothetical. So, I don't
have any skin in the game. So please
take advice from somebody who has actual
skill in the game, not someone like me.
Okay. All the best sir. I hope things
things become fine soon.
Pratip Kumar Roy says Technos J Bharat
is asking did European colonial powers
miss the historical opportunity to
reoccupy the US during the 1861 civil
war just like the US colonized Europe
along with the USSR after World War II?
No.
Uh so the US had its civil war in 1861
but none of the European nations at the
time had the ability the capability to
cross the Atlantic with a big invasion
force. Okay. And then mount a proper
successful invasion of the US. It was
impossible.
Impossible.
So no they did not miss this historical
opportunity. So which were the major
European powers at this time 1861? You
had the UK.
Even the UK with its major Royal Navy
and all did not have uh the capability
to cross the Atlantic with a major
invading force and launch a proper
invasion of the US. Even the UK UK did
not have that. Who else were the major
powers in 1861?
Spain wasn't that great anymore, right?
Germany was still not unified at the
time. It was unified in 18 in 1871.
So it was still a decade away from
unification. So the only major power
great power in Europe at the time was
the UK. You had the Habsburg Empire and
all the the the AustroHungarian Empire
was still was it there at the time?
Let's say it was let's say it was
AustroHungarian Empire. It's it was not
a major maritime power. So I think there
was no European power at that time that
had the wherewithal and the capability
to mount a successful invasion of the US
by crossing the Atlantic. It was not
possible. Now
okay Adita says Trump called Modi on the
Iran war. The US sees India as a key
regional power. Reports of Mus joining
the call denied by India. What do you
what do I think?
Um what I think is that Trump wants
something from us.
Okay? Otherwise he will not call Modi.
He has a favor to ask or he has some
demands to make. That's why he must have
called Mr. Modi.
Um
he said the US says that they see India
as a key regional player. Well, thank
you for your nice words. We don't give a
damn.
Okay. We are what we are. I don't care
what you see us as. We are what we are.
We are a regional player. Yeah. We are a
regional power. And why are we a
regional power? Why are we not more than
a regional power? Because the Americans
have this policy of containment. It's
containment policy towards India. And so
they are not behaving like a friendly
nation.
So um and reports of Musk joining the
call denied by India. So, did somebody
claim that Elon Musk joined the call?
Uh, let's see what uh social what what
this has to say. Did Elon Musk join the
call between Trump and Modi recently?
The recent call?
The recent call between Trump and Modi.
So, the New York Times claims that Trump
joined in the phone call.
Trump Modi conversation says government
which government
Trump Modi after reports
okay the New York Times claimed that
Musk was there so what does the New York
Times have to say I don't subscribe to
these guys so I don't know let's see
reject
okay payw wall has hit so I can't so the
New York Times seems to be claiming that
Trump uh so that must join the call. I
can't see what what is the rationale for
that. What what are what they're saying?
What are the details? Um but the
government of India has denied the call.
So what do I think? I think the
Americans So I there are two
possibilities. Either Musk was there or
Musk wasn't there. If Musk wasn't there,
then the Americans are trying to
complicate things by claiming Musk was
there and they're trying to pressurize
India somehow by inserting Musk into the
thing. But if Musk was actually there in
the American telling the truth that
maybe India wants to play a different
game and say that Musk wasn't there. So
I don't know what exactly happened. Uh
but these these are games that are
played in geopolitics right but why did
Trump call Modi? He probably has some
demand to make. I suppose that's why he
would have called Modi. Otherwise he
won't call. Right. Okay.
Sorb says can we tell if an ICBM is
nuclear or not once launched? We simply
can't tell what package it is carrying.
We can't tell. How do we tell?
You can't tell that whether a missile is
carrying a conventional warhead or a
nuclear warhead or no warhead at all.
You can't tell. And that's the big
issue. You can't.
Ob says, "What's your ultimate purpose
in life?" My ultimate purpose in life is
to live life to the fullest. um
experience as much as possible good
things right and uh hopefully give more
to society than I take from it that I
think that's that's enough that's enough
for me
says good evening ma'am good evening
history session next week please you are
fantastic thank you so much ma'am I
will I have the time to do a ne see
there's so much happening I next week
I'm planning to do at least three
sessions but if I insert a history
session there I'm not sure if that is
going to be possible I I know that
history is important and that's why I do
so many of those. But right now the
situation is such that I focus on the
war. So I'll see if it's possible if if
the war you know calms down then I'll
insert a history session otherwise in
the future. But I really appreciate you
ma'am. I really really appreciate the
wonderful questions you ask. So we'll do
a history session as soon as possible.
All right. Okay. Pratib Kumar Roy says
why doesn't the government ban all the
Christianized Hindu organizations
supported funded and founded by
Freemasons? Only the government can
answer these questions. Uh
Freemasons are there
I haven't looked into the role of
Freemasons in in India so I don't know
about the Freemasons but u yeah this is
a question I suppose only the government
of India can answer. I can't answer on
their behalf. Yeah, we obviously should
should take actions and measures to to
end the foreign interference what
whatever form it takes in our country.
Yeah.
All right. So that is this is the last
super chat for the day. Good night
everyone. Good night everyone. Thank you
so much everybody for the questions. I
will call it a day over here. Let's end
the live stream at this point. So thank
you so much everybody. Take care. Keep
asking questions. Keep keep learning,
keep raising your standards, and I will
see you very soon in the next one, which
will happen, I'm pretty sure, very soon.
Until then, take care. See you soon.
Bye-bye.